<entries>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_REPEAT_ACT3">&lt;page=S&gt;Miss courier! Pharloom&#8217;s bugs are wishing, waiting, sad and scared. The deliverings are needed, now more than more!</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_RELICS_FIRST">But what&#8217;s this?! I smell something on you right now! You have a relic for me!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_FIX_OFFER">Aha! The spines! Specimen, you have them! Then it is time, indeed! Bzzt! To free you of your wriggling torment, and show my genius clear! </entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_CURSED">Oh my, what a state you&#8217;re in! You look like you&#8217;re one breath away from keeling over dead!&lt;hpage&gt;I will continue to live, madam, but I am indeed afflicted. A parasite has taken root within my shell... Perhaps you have something that could help me? A medicine?&lt;page&gt;Mmm, not so sure I stock anything like that. You should ask Pavo there. It&#8217;s his job to give directions and such, so he may have some useful advice.&lt;page&gt;In the meantime... shopping itself is a type of medicine, isn&#8217;t it? You should buy something now. Given your condition, this might be your last chance!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_CURSED_TALK_1">&lt;page=S&gt;Ughhh! What-what is this? Your body is all twisting, creaking! Horrid fiend inside! &lt;hpage&gt;A parasite has lodged deep inside my shell. It has taken some strength of will to keep its thrashing at bay.&lt;page=T&gt;With a shell like such, you cannot be taking no deliverings! Infect the goods you would-would!&lt;hpage&gt;Very well, couriers. If I somehow manage to remove the parasite, I may return to offer aid.</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_MEET">What do you want, slave?&lt;hpage&gt;Slave? I am a traveller, stranger, not a slave.&lt;page&gt;Grnk. Exactly what a slave would say. Begone!</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_REPEAT2_ACT3">&lt;hpage&gt;Soon, Pavo, I shall calm the chaos. Please guard these bugs safe till then.&lt;page&gt;Of course, dear resident! Of course! Know all our faith, and our wishes go with you.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_ROSARYSTRING_M_DESC">Loose rosaries will escape your pockets at the worst of times, and I&#8217;m a deft claw at stringing them tight! I can string you a whole necklace, safe and stylish.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHORT_QUEST_ACCEPTED">&lt;hpage&gt;I have taken your wish, Tipp. If I find your brother safe, I&#8217;ll be sure to send him back this way.&lt;page&gt;My many thanks, miss saving! You are brave-brave. Same as brother! My faith goes all with you!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_REPEAT">Up there, in that Citadel, the fabled oil is waiting. Bestow it upon this fine pinmaster and your blade shall sing louder yet.&lt;hpage&gt;I will find the oil, pinmaster. Keep your skills sharp.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_OFFER">Now now! What&#8217;s all this? Infested are you, bzzt?&lt;page&gt;Do you even know who I am? Why, &#8216;tis the great Yarnaby, genius physician, unfairly outcast, who now towers before you!&lt;hpage&gt;I apologise for intruding upon your work, but if you are the skilled physician you claim, I ask your assistance.&lt;hpage&gt;A parasite has wormed its way inside of me. Its roots twist and pull inside my shell, draining my strength. If you possess the skills and tools, I would see it removed.&lt;page&gt;Bzzt! Well, well! So you&#8217;re a special, sickly specimen, are you?! That changes matters, yes. Turns them on their head!&lt;page&gt;Let me see. Hm. Not haunted, indeed. No Silk-sickness. But something strange has certainly clawed its way in!&lt;page&gt;These &#8220;roots&#8221; that torment you so... I&#8217;m not altogether familiar with them, but it matters not!&lt;page&gt;If there&#8217;s something nasty inside a shell that must come out, we use great Yarnaby&#8217;s Extricator! It&#8217;s your only hope, bzzt!&lt;page&gt;...Hmmm, but to crack your stiff shell we&#8217;ll first need some extra strength. The healing can be done, yes! But before that my mighty Extricator needs an upgrade!</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_SHARD_POUCH">Travellers should always keep spare shards close by. We Bellharters were once renown for our fine claw-work. An art lost on most modern pilgrims... excepting yourself I&#8217;m sure.</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_SAVED_3">What a persistent little worm you are. Amuse me then. Why did you cut those poor bugs from their comforting curse?&lt;hpage&gt;There was old power in the creature that guided the thread, and a talent of Silk, now taken, that shall prove useful to me.&lt;hpage&gt;That the town is freed and its service returned is a benefit too. I may ofttimes feel myself apart from these bugs, but even I recoil to see Silk strung in such sickening service.&lt;page&gt;Grnk. To free them was no favour. But the gathering of power... In that goal, we may understand each other some.</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_RELICS">Ahh... I smell something on you. Heavy with the past, you are. You have a relic for me, don&#8217;t you?</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_OFFER">&lt;hpage&gt;Your skills are impressive. My needle sings from your care. But I must ask, can the blade be honed further?&lt;page&gt;You seek further sharpening? Further than Plinney does provide? Impertinence! But... Maybe? But... No...&lt;hpage&gt;You hesitate? Then it is possible? Are you incapable? Should I seek others within the kingdom?&lt;page&gt;Wait! Yes. Seek not others, but an oil, fabled and fine. With it the Citadel once brought gleaming edge and point to its pins.&lt;page&gt;Though the Citadel&#8217;s pinmasters are long past, some small store of that miraculous elixir may remain within its halls.&lt;page&gt;Were even a meagre drop pilfered, and gifted upon Plinney, your blade could shine brighter still...&lt;page&gt;Just know, dear friend, the veiled bugs would be oh so unkind to the thief who&#8217;d claim that fine prize for themself.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_TOOL_POUCH_DESC">You&#8217;ve a tool pouch on you? I can add a few pockets so you can carry more tools, and more shards to make&#8217;em. My sewing skills are quite renowned in these parts.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_MEET">&lt;page=S&gt;Miss saving! We are together, at last! My brother and myself, both returned to safety&#8217;s safe.&lt;hpage&gt;I am pleased you have found one another. If you are planning to venture out again, I would urge you reconsider for the sake of your shells.&lt;page=S&gt;We know it! Muchly-much! We cannot be leaving this home of bells. No more! Heres we will remain, for shells to survive. &lt;page=T&gt;But we instead did plan, together, clever! Yes-yes. Those pilgrims, them that pass, maybes they will help? For small reward as we have?&lt;page=T&gt;Even you, miss saving! Yes-yes! Saving is done. Our wishes now we ask. Now is time for miss courier!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_REOFFER">Lost within that fortress above, the fabled oil of my profession... Such sharpness one could achieve...&lt;page&gt;But, oh! &#8216;Tis an awful thing. Too cruel, the many stabbing pins you&#8217;d face in its seeking.</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_PAINT_POST">We&#8217;ve made a good start on the painting, resident! Give us a little more time and your bell&#8217;ll be shining like new.</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_SNARE">Hnff... So the slave comes seeking?&lt;page&gt;I&#8217;ve heard it. Wishing on a world cut free, yes? Along with my nephew up there. Sounds he&#8217;s sunk as simple as you.&lt;hpage&gt;Will you not provide your aid, bug? This trap he plans requires power, and I suspect you&#8217;re hoarding more than most.&lt;page&gt;Oh no. I&#8217;ll give it. Not in the hope you&#8217;ll succeed... Bah! In that, there&#8217;s slim chance. I give just to see that restless energy unleashed.&lt;page&gt;So much soul, found and formed. Generations of it, all going to waste. Better it&#8217;s given a chance to blaze.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_DOOR_INSPECT">A locked bellhome.&lt;br&gt;Call out?</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_LIFEBLOOD_STATE">&lt;hpage&gt;Madam, my shell has been overcome by a foreign force. Plasmium it has been called in your land.&lt;hpage&gt;Though the substance provides some regenerative aid, I feel my mind at dangerous risk of being overtaken.&lt;page&gt;Bzzt! Maybe overtaken is good? Better even? Why go thinking yours is a mind so precious?&lt;page&gt;The great Yarnaby treats the sick! Not those that benefit from their afflictions. Enjoy its advantage and leave me in peace!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHORT_MEET">Miss Saving! Thanks again for you and your big-big blade! I&#8217;m is made it back, and grumpy grub-grub got her goods. She seemed happy, even!&lt;page&gt;I&#8217;m won&#8217;t be travelling out for a while-while methinks. Too many beasties! All about theys are. Even those pilgrims! All now going angry, a bit like old grub-grub.&lt;hpage&gt;This town remains safe for the moment, Tipp. You&#8217;re a smart bug to stay within its walls.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_INPROGRESS_1">&lt;page=S&gt;Keep safe, miss courier! You and your deliverings, fragile both can be!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_INPROGRESS_3">&lt;page=T&gt;Do not wait, miss courier! You hold the deliverings, so nows you must away! A quick-quick bug, you must become yourself.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHORT_GOURMAND_HINT">&lt;hpage&gt;Tipp, I have promised a wish to an old bug of the Citadel, ingredients for a dish to stir a gourmand&#8217;s stomach.&lt;hpage&gt;Do you hold in your belongings a Courier&#8217;s Rasher? It seems a key element.&lt;page&gt;Courier&#8217;s Rasher! Not me, miss savings! Smelly, fatty foods, good for most. Not good for my sensitive stomach!&lt;page&gt;You want-want my brother, Pill! Pill is big. Pill loves rashers! Can prepare them fresh for you, but first, Pill must be found, saved, safe-safe!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CLOSED_QUEST_END">Bzzt! What now?! Not another bother for the great Yarnaby?&lt;hpage&gt;Madam, I have returned with the spines requested. Allow me to enter, that you may remove this parasite from my shell.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_PROMPT">Sharpen Needle?</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADED_COMPLETE">That blade! By claw! My finest work by far. Pharloom may ail, but across its morbid dim, your needle will shine bright. </entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_SPA_DESC">Care to refresh yourself in a steaming spa? Given your hard labours, I&#8217;m sure your shell would thank you for it.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_LIGHTS_DESC">Twine strung globes filled with gleamflies. These&#8217;ll brighten up even the darkest bell.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_DUSTPENSSLAVE_RETRY">&lt;page=S&gt;Another egg. Another grossy eater queen. Delivery for the big-big creature beyond the roaches. Maybe this one travels safer than last?</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_SLAP_PRE">Specimen, we must! There are secrets to uncover, bzzt! Progress can not be denied!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_CURSED_REPEAT">&lt;page=T&gt;With your shell all a&#8217;wriggle, you can&#8217;t be taking no deliverings! Infect the goods you would!&lt;hpage&gt;Very well, couriers. If I somehow manage to remove the parasite, I may return to offer aid.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_ACCEPT">Bzzt! Bravo! A specimen who sees my brilliance!&lt;page&gt;The task for you is simple. Head over into that tangled mess of cages, on the roads above the moors.&lt;page&gt;Two bugs hide away there, Benjin and Crull. Simple types, woefully ignorant... yet they have been useful in procuring me materials.&lt;page&gt;It&#8217;s Steel Spines I need. A full bundle of them, forged hard and sharp. Tougher than I&#8217;ve ever had. Tough enough to crack stone! And to pierce your thick shell, bzzt!&lt;hpage&gt;Then prepare your machine for my return, madam. I shall soon return with the spines, for I am eager to see myself freed.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_DESK_NAME">Desk</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_ACCEPT">&lt;hpage&gt;I will find the oil, pinmaster. My needle has seen much use in this cruel kingdom, and I suspect many more battles are due. I will value your further skills upon my blade. &lt;page&gt;It is a dangerous wish you accept of this poor pinmaster. I welly hope this one&#8217;s professional desire does not cost you your life.</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_CURSED_REPEAT">If you insist on surviving your infestation, seek the one exiled from Bellhart, little Yarnaby. She was chased out, high up into the moors, last I heard.</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_GOT">Yes... this fits my collection well. Look, then! Look at what I have!</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_REPEAT">I&#8217;ll waste no more words on a slave. Begone.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_FIXER_RETRY">&lt;page=T&gt;More deliverings for those sad survivors in their cave below. &lt;page=S&gt;Deliver them quick-quick, miss courier! They will help much.</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_TWISTED_BUD_HINT">That cry upon you, sister! Those are the sour sobs of a grey and twisted thing.&lt;hpage&gt;You speak of the bud? It is a mysterious thing indeed. In the dank swamps above the moor, I sought towards its plaintive wails, and found it resting there... Waiting, it almost seemed.&lt;hpage&gt;But you speak of its form, without sighting it upon me. Is it a thing familiar to you?... Have you heard these cries before?&lt;page&gt;Aye, yes! Not your own specimen, surely, but way back, other travellers did sometimes carry similar. Odd types they all were. Offerings they&#8217;d call the crying things, and towards the core of Shellwood they would trek.&lt;page&gt;Never I did see one again, not the buds nor the bugs that brought the gift...&lt;page&gt;If you&#8217;re planning to follow their path, I&#8217;ll wish on your safety, but &#8216;tis an ill omen to hear such sad sounds returned after so long.</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_MEET">What? What, what? Who is it? What&#8217;ve you got? What do you want?&lt;hpage&gt;I am just a traveller, one hoping you were not too badly affected by the cursed snare set upon this town.&lt;page&gt;Pah! What binds them outside means nothing to me. None of them have my keen sense, my respect for the past!&lt;page&gt;You seem able, though. Sneaky, too. If you find any fine old stuff, anything with a history to it, bring it here. I&#8217;ll take it.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_COMPLETED">And now! This pinmaster must work! Let the sharpening begin!</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_SAVED_1_ALT">Hff. The noise from above has returned, that pitiful clamour. The threads have been cut.&lt;page&gt;You... It was you who cut them. Do not deny it!&lt;hpage&gt;Why should I deny it, sir? I defeated the cruel creature above the town, and awoke the old bell stilled by Silk. Are you displeased?&lt;page&gt;Displeased! If I breathe, if I live, I am displeased. Only the dead are satisfied.&lt;page&gt;You are a slave, and a nuisance... begone.</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_TALK1_ACT3">Resident! What a marvel you are, continuing to dare the wilds and darkness, and returning home to us unscathed.&lt;hpage&gt;I return with hope worth sharing, Pavo. I have seen a way to calm this chaos, one I now work swiftly towards.&lt;hpage&gt;The chance remains slim, but if this town can hold, and my efforts succeed, Pharloom may see a future yet.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_GRAMAPHONE_DESC">The Citadel crafted some marvellous machines, and this looks to be one of its finest! Apparently sent by some creepy slitherer hidden away up there, for sale only to you! </entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_EMPTY">It&#8217;s my calling it is, to gather the relics of the past. If you find any fine old stuff, anything with a history to it, bring it here. I&#8217;ll take it.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_NOTACCEPTED">&lt;hpage&gt;I can not aid you, couriers. Not now. My own tasks are too pressing to consider taking on your deliveries. &lt;hpage&gt;With luck, some pilgrims may pass with sound mind and strength remaining. They may choose to promise your wishes.&lt;page=T&gt;Then we shall pray they come, miss saving! Our thanks go muchly with you, still.</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_SAVED_1">Hff. The noise from above has returned, that pitiful clamour. The threads have been cut.&lt;page&gt;You... It was you who cut them down. Do not deny it!&lt;hpage&gt;Why should I deny it, sir? I severed the thread and defeated the creature guiding the curse unto the town. Are you displeased?&lt;page&gt;Displeased! If I breathe, if I live, I am displeased. Only the dead are satisfied.&lt;page&gt;You are a slave, and a nuisance... begone.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_FLEATOPIA">&lt;page=T&gt;We&#8217;s heard the word! Many fleas together, settled high in Pharloom, calling out their wants of us!&lt;page=T&gt;Clever grubbers, fleas, but theys too need-need our deliverings. See them served, miss courier! Always goodly-good to gain the thanks of fleas.</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_MEET_ALT">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, shopkeeper. I&#8217;d ask to trade, but your store seems a little bare.&lt;page&gt;Ahem! Well, yes. Our little town&#8217;s seen some dire times, and now my courier&#8217;s gone and got themself lost.&lt;page&gt;But don&#8217;t worry! I&#8217;ve a few small things, still! And if that courier ever makes it safely back, we&#8217;ll have plenty more treasures to haggle over.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_LIFEBLOOD_STATE_REPEAT">Bzzt! Leave me in peace! The great Yarnaby treats the sick! Not those that benefit from their afflictions. Enjoy its advantage and leave me in peace!&lt;hpage&gt;Very well, madam. I did not mean to waste your time.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_FINISHED">Bonva! It is done, brave warrior. By my expert claw, your strange blade has received some fast-sharp shine. It shall cut cleaner than ever before.&lt;hpage&gt;Your efforts provide great aid, pinmaster. You have my thanks.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_MEET_ACT3">&lt;page=T&gt;Miss courier! What horror here! The caves shake-shake, crying pain of hurt most savage.&lt;page=T&gt;And see all our poor friends below, newly found, crowded inside this home of bells, hearts fast for fear.&lt;page=S&gt;But what-what for you? You are here to help, yes-yes? The deliverings, they are needed now at most! When caves turn dark, the deliverings are essential, more than more.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BROKEN">&lt;page=T&gt;The deliverings! They are broken-broke! Gone and spilled!&lt;page=T&gt;Do not lose hearty-heart, miss courier! This is Pharloom! Danger, deadly. In times as these, is a rarer thing for goods to get to their goings.&lt;page=S&gt;Would you try-try again? For the bugs so much in need of their deliverings?</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_SAVED_2">Those bugs, cowering in their gleaming bells. Grnk. They claim a common calling, to serve the pilgrims as they make their path upwards.&lt;page&gt;Such a crucial role they award themselves, surely worthy of praise!&lt;page&gt;A sweet lie, of course. They, like their predecessors, are simply too weak and fearful to venture any farther. A settlement born from indolence.</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_MEET_ACCEPTEDWISH">&lt;hpage&gt;He would have been wise to do so. If, on my travels, I happen upon the errant bug, I&#8217;ll make sure to send him your way.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_BELLTOWN_MEET_OFFER">By claw! Are you then our saviour in the shell? Standing so calm and cool on entrance to Plinney&#8217;s bellhome!&lt;hpage&gt;What clue, sir, tells of my part in your town&#8217;s liberation?&lt;page&gt;Why your blade, fierce warrior! Any fine pinmaster would detect the sign of deadly work upon that needle&#8217;s edge.&lt;page&gt;T&#8217;was a vile curse that struck here. No simple bug, nor basic pin could have granted our release. No!&lt;page&gt;That blade though, so expertly clutched in claw. That could welly have met the task. It was you cut us free, yes?&lt;hpage&gt;I&#8217;ll grant you&#8217;ve sharp sight, pinmaster, and your saving is fortuitous. This blade that restored your town would now benefit from your service.&lt;page&gt;Welly, yes! I&#8217;ve a busy backlog of pins to tend, but your gracious heroism decrees that unique weapon receives my care this very moment! What&#8217;s say I take a look?</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_POSTWINDOW">More, then! Bring me more relics of the past! Records, seals, idols! Let&#8217;s gather up the history of the world and hoard it all here, nice and safe!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_REPEAT">&lt;page=S&gt;Many deliverings still need making, miss courier! We is much needing your help, when you is ready for the giving of it-it!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_UPGRADED">Done, it is! Marvel of Pharloom! See how it gleams, your long, fine blade. Havast! That the pins of our land all once held such shine. So much we have lost...&lt;hpage&gt;This is fine service, pinmaster. It has been a long age since I have seen my needle such. I had not remembered the finesse of its forging.&lt;page&gt;Welly, ho! It is certain! Yours is a blade of finer make than most, one of few that could bear even more sharpening.&lt;page&gt;If ever upon your long road more oil is acquired, seek my service with haste! Who knows what form we could find deeper within your weapon&#8217;s sharpened steel!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_NOTACCEPTED_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;For the moment, I can not aid you, couriers. My own tasks are too pressing.&lt;page=T&gt;Then we shall hope you see them soon achieved! If the deliverings are not made, Pharloom&#8217;s bugs will suffer muchly-much!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_BELLTOWN_POST_SAVED">&lt;hpage&gt;It is fortune to see you returned, pinmaster. The roads between here and that deep woods&#8217; grave crawl with violent foes. I had concerns for your safety.&lt;page&gt;Brave warrior, my hero! T&#8217;was indeed a fearful scramble home, but safe I now am! And a warmly pleasure to see you too for the world has darkened indeed!&lt;page&gt;In such times, the task for a pinmaster is clear, to polish and sharpen and refine, suchly that the glimmer of your blade may pierce through the encroaching murk!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_DUSTPENSSLAVE">&lt;page=S&gt;We is got requested times a&#8217;many for this, a queeny egg of those eaters of Silk. Wish from big, sticky creature, near many roaches caged. Wants it muchly! &lt;hpage&gt;The creature, I have met them, a timid, fawning sort. Nonetheless, their tending of Silkeaters can be a benefit for me.&lt;hpage&gt;If a queen delivered could improve their harvest, I too would gain from the trade.&lt;page=S&gt;Miss courier, and big, sticky creature? Both are like to liking things so grossly-gross? We think yous are muchly strange...</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_FIRST_MEET_ACT3">&lt;page=T&gt;Miss saving! We thought us safe, brothers together at last, but what horror even here! The caves shake-shake, crying pain of hurt most savage.&lt;page=T&gt;And see all our poor friends below, newly found, crowded inside this home of bells, hearts fast for fear.&lt;page=S&gt;But what-what for you? You are here to help, yes-yes? The deliverings, they are needed now at most! Alas, for our shells to survive we cannot now leave this home of bells. No more. Heres we must remain.&lt;page=T&gt;But we instead did plan, together, clever! Yes-yes. Those strong ones, like yourselfs, maybes they will help? For small reward as we have?&lt;page=S&gt;Our savings is done, and the caves turn dark. Now the deliveries are needed, desperate. Now is time for miss courier! </entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_MEET_ALT">What? What, what? Who is it? What&#8217;ve you got? What do you want?&lt;hpage&gt;I am just a traveller. May I ask, though, what work occupies you here?&lt;page&gt;What occupies me, you ask? The past! The voices of ages gone by, they speak to me through what is left behind.&lt;page&gt;Those outside, those dreary pilgrims and bell-adorned dullards... none of them have my keen sense, my respect for the past!&lt;page&gt;You seem able, though. Sneaky, too. If you find any fine old stuff, anything with a history to it, bring it here. I&#8217;ll take it.</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_HOUSE_MID_TALK">Your continued help to Bellhart has not gone unnoticed, miss traveller.&lt;page&gt;In these terrible times, it&#8217;s rare enough to see any wish granted. Now to see such care come from a stranger! Why, that&#8217;s simply unheard of!&lt;hpage&gt;I have seen the scale of suffering wrought across Pharloom, Pavo. And I will admit, fulfilling these requests may do little to affect the cause... Even still, I have found it a rewarding task.&lt;hpage&gt;To aid another... The small warmth of it, I had almost forgotten.</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_NO_RELICS">It&#8217;s my calling it is, to gather the relics of the past. Look at my collection, if you fancy! Look, look!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_BONETOWNFIXER_RETRY">&lt;page=T&gt;Goods for the camp at base, where pilgrims&#8217; journey starts. We muchly hope this delivering goes well!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_INPROGRESS_2">&lt;page=S&gt;You have the good-goods, miss courier! Now only the deliverings needs doing. Don&#8217;t wait here-here!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_REPEAT">Off with you! Head over to that tangled mess of cages, in those roads above the moors.&lt;page&gt;Those two bugs, Benjin and Crull, can surely scrounge up what I need. A full bundle of hard, sharp spines!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_4_POST">That blade! By claw! It is done. Sharper than this pinmaster would have believed achievable. Shining pale and clear.&lt;page&gt;Bonva! Stranger, you have granted my wish, and more. Your blade is accomplishment to match those of great pinmasters past.&lt;page&gt;Pharloom may ail, but throughout its morbid dim, your needle will shine bright. </entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_DECLINE">What? You refuse to pass it on? What good do you think it&#8217;ll do you?!</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_REPEAT_ACT3">&lt;hpage&gt;Stay safe, Pavo. Keep these poor bugs close and their spirits from sorrow.&lt;page&gt;None shall leave these walls, dear resident, and all still are welcome. Any that can be saved.&lt;page&gt;Better we bugs be together, here at the end of it all.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_SAVED_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;Stay alert on your journey home, pinmaster. If you encounter other bugs upon the road, I advise you avoid them as you are able.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_SLAP_POST">Auugh! Bzzt! Again the world lashes out at me!&lt;page&gt;But the pain... it means nothing to Yarnaby!&lt;page&gt;Nothing can deter my great work! Not for long! I must not be stopped!</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_PAINT_NAME">Bell Lacquer</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_FIXER">&lt;page=S&gt;A new destination this-this! And desperate these supplies are asked.&lt;page=T&gt;Deliverings for them-them escaped from the crumbled camp beside the bone, those few still living.&lt;page=T&gt;Hurting and hungry, those few must be. </entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_GOURMAND">&lt;page=T&gt;It is yours, miss courier! Meats prepared fresh as fresh, in our special way.&lt;page=T&gt;Miss courier must know! Our rasher is delicious, strong, fatty food, but is not long to last. If not stored quick, it-it is flavour fast turns foul.&lt;hpage&gt;If the rasher is likely to spoil, then I shall make fast for the Citadel. I&#8217;ve no desire to see your efforts, or your scant supplies wasted.</entry>
<entry name="FISHER_DLG_03">Shellwood&#8217;s grown more dangerous in recent times, but I&#8217;m a lifelong catcher, right down to my core. Ain&#8217;t nothing that&#8217;ll change that. </entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_MULTIBIND">I rarely sell objects as intriguing as this. Supposed to improve a bug&#8217;s natural ability to heal! Can&#8217;t say I&#8217;ve felt its effects myself, but then I keep more healthy than most.</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_MEET_ACT3">What? What now? What&#8217;s all that great racket, what is it?&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, ma&#8217;am. If you are disturbed by the rending of these lands, I fear some blame is mine to bear.&lt;page&gt;Pah. I care not for the miseries and struggles of them outside! None of them have my keen sense, my respect for the past!&lt;page&gt;You seem able, though. Sneaky, too. If you find any fine old stuff, anything with a history to it, bring it here. I&#8217;ll take it.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_DECLINED">Ahh. &#8216;Tis your choice, warrior. If you&#8217;re choosing different in times ahead, Plinney shall be here to provide eager aid.</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_CURSED">My sickly friend! Pavo can sense that you are ailing, but fret not! For in Bellhart, pilgrims may rest and recuperate until they are fit to travel once more!&lt;hpage&gt;Your hospitality is appreciated, Pavo, but I fear rest alone will not suffice for this illness. A parasite has taken root inside me, one I can not remove through strength alone.&lt;hpage&gt;Tell me, are there any you know who might help me? A healer, or a physician?&lt;page&gt;A physician? Well... we did once have one... A frightening fiend! Callous and crude in her practice. For the health of glorious Bellhart we voted, unanimously, to expel her!&lt;page&gt;I know not where she buzzed away to, and I prefer to keep it that way! But if you really must seek her out, you might start by speaking to the old hermit skulking beneath the Bellway.&lt;page&gt;Yes... that hermit seems mad, but he has a way of accumulating knowledge. He might be able to tell you where that wretched physician is lurking.</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_HOUSE_FULL_REPEAT">We are lucky to have you, miss traveller. In Bellhart you are always welcome, you and your big, sharp blade!</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_TALK_1">&lt;hpage&gt;What do you remember of your time caught upon the thread, Pavo?&lt;page&gt;Oh, ahh. It is difficult... Upsetting even to think. Strange, sad memories, not my own, and my own thoughts smothered amidst the tangle.&lt;page&gt;If one could choose to connect themself to something grander, that curse may seem a wonder. For myself, it now seems a horror.</entry>
<entry name="SPINNER_INTRO">Oh! Ohhhh! They shall join... Union upon your thread... A gift, for your waking. A world strung to serve...&lt;hpage&gt;Creature, your claws guide those cursed threads but you are not their source. What role do you play in this vile affliction?</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_FIRSTDELIVERY">&lt;page=T&gt;But hold, miss courier! Before depart you mustly know, all deliverings are in needing of great-great care!&lt;page=S&gt;No bump! No shake! No taking funny transport! Only leg, claw, wing must be used to see them where they need be going.&lt;page=S&gt;Carry the deliverings safe-safe, miss courier! Cared for like your own shell.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_FLEATOPIA_RETRY">&lt;page=T&gt;Those good-goods, all packed fresh for the clever fleas. Take thems up for us, miss courier. Maybe new friends you might be making with your service? Yes-yes? </entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CLOSED">Bzzt! Who&#8217;s bothering me now?! Leave the great Yarnaby in peace! Shoo shoo!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CLOSED_CURSED">&lt;hpage&gt;I am sick, madam, and badly in need of your service. I&#8217;ve become host to a vile infestation. It leeches my strength, and attempts to wrest control of my shell.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CONVO_1">Halfwits, the lot of them! Such great achievement, wrought by Yarnaby! A bug healed full by my marvellous machine!&lt;page&gt;A few weaklings expire, and they all raise their claws. Is there no place for progress in their tiny minds?!</entry>
<entry name="FISHER_DLG_02">Bellhart&#8217;s lost much of its lustre, but we still offer some comfort to the pilgrims who climb this high.</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_MEET_ACT3">&lt;page&gt;Dear resident! To see you return alive is such a glimmer of light, even as the dark descends upon us all.&lt;hpage&gt;All these pilgrims gathered here... I had not expected so many to survive. The destruction beyond these bells suggested worse.&lt;page&gt;Indeed! Things should be worse! Would be worse, but for your tall warrior friend, her of those shining rings, who so fortunately chose our town to camp.&lt;page&gt;That brave bug now acts alone to guard our town and those pilgrims who flee for it.&lt;page&gt;For her efforts, our shells have stayed safe, though how long she can remain at that task... I do not dare to consider.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHORT_QUEST_AVAILABLE">My brother, Pill, still out there. Help-help others he must be, taking good-goods all across. I&#8217;m is only hope he stay safe-safe, but gone long is Pill. Too long!&lt;page&gt;On the wishwall, I&#8217;m placed my wish-wish, that my brother returns to me, and these bells of safety&#8217;s safe.&lt;hpage&gt;I shall check the wall, Tipp. If your wish aligns with my journey, I may track him down.</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_MEET_EXPANDED_ALT">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, shopkeeper. Given the hardships of the lands beyond these bells, your store seems in remarkable order. &lt;page&gt;Aye, well, we&#8217;ve had our tough times too! Of once bustling Bellhart, only a few residents now remain.&lt;page&gt;But things are turned around for old Frey! Ho, yes! The town at least feels briefly at peace, and my courier has returned with fresh goods to trade. &lt;page&gt;Whether pilgrim or traveller, mine is the finest store you&#8217;ll have the fortune to visit throughout our blighted lands.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_SPA_NAME">Personal Spa</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_SAVED_COURIER_1">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings again, shopkeeper. Your shelves are looking better stocked. I see the courier made their way back to you safely.&lt;page&gt;Oh yes, the cheeky little so-and-so came by and dropped his cargo off at last.&lt;page&gt;Poor dear was so shaken by his misadventures, I almost didn&#8217;t have the heart to dock his earnings.&lt;page&gt;All&#8217;s well now, though! Take a look at the lovely new goods I have available!</entry>
<entry name="SPINNER_INTRO_2">Ohhhh! She is here! The rare birthling! Precious child of Wyrm and Weaver!&lt;page&gt;Spawn of those who dared to flee. She has found her way home... at last.&lt;page&gt;How fine her shell, and Silk, and claw... For you, mother... let me claim her all for you!</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_FURNISHING">A fine purchase you&#8217;ve made! Allow us a moment and we&#8217;ll get it set up in your bellhome.</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_CYLINDER">Ah! That relic you possess! A cylinder of the Citadel&#8217;s sacred vault! That there is a mighty find. You will give it, yes?&lt;hpage&gt;I will not, seeker. To extract what knowledge it holds, this cylinder requires a listening device, one you do not possess.&lt;hpage&gt;If it were passed, whatever secrets it contains would remain forever hidden from us both.&lt;page&gt;Pah... If it will not speak to me, I do not want it! Don&#8217;t trouble me until you have something worth my taking!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BROKEN_SHORT">&lt;page=T&gt;The deliverings, all broken-broke? Would you try-try again, miss courier? Pharloom&#8217;s bugs are so much in need of your help!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_CANCOMPLETE_REOFFER">Bonva, traveller! You have the oil! Will you allow me to work wonder upon your blade?</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_MEET_ALT">Welcome, welcome, weary pilgrim! Though glorious Bellhart may be past its finest shine, it still remains the last friendly stop before the Citadel. &lt;page&gt;It is the task of I, fair Pavo, to extend the warmest of welcome to those passing devout, such as your good self!&lt;page&gt;Now! I insist you enjoy our remaining hospitality, if only for a moment. We&#8217;ve wares to buy and services to enjoy!&lt;page&gt;Even in our reduced state, you&#8217;ll find ours as cozy a stop as can be offered in these ailing lands.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_DECLINE">Welly, nay? Certainly you make the safer choice. Better to keep one&#8217;s shell intact. </entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_PILGRIMSREST_RETRY">&lt;page=T&gt;Supplies for the rest-stop in the fields. We is used to like this delivering, when we was young and muchly brave.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHORT_REPEAT">This town feel safe, just, but I&#8217;m is worries for others. Is Pharloom needing its good-goods?&lt;page&gt;Many bugs helped by us couriers, me and brother Pill. Special now when danger grows big-big. </entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_TAKEN_COURIER_1">I saw it! Took my wish off the board, you did! Heading out after my stray courier, then?&lt;hpage&gt;My own tasks see me travel far, shopkeeper. If, on my journey, I happen upon the errant bug, I&#8217;ll make sure to send them your way.&lt;page&gt;Then you&#8217;ll have my thanks and more! It&#8217;s a rare bug who&#8217;d brave the wilds to aid a fellow.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_SPOOL_SEGMENT_DESC">For a spool bearing no Silk, it&#8217;s surprisingly heavy. Do you think perhaps it could be a gift left behind by the old creeping ones?</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_CURSED_REPEAT">If you really must find that wretched physician, speak to the old hermit lurking beneath Bellhart. He knows much more than he admits of the world...</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_3_POST">Welly, done! What miracle to work again upon steel so fine. Few pins left in Pharloom could attain such a sheen!&lt;page&gt;You must tell me, traveller, wherever did you come upon so splendid a weapon?&lt;hpage&gt;The blade was a gift, given by a noble tribe of my homeland. They forged the strongest steel, though it was rarely seen beyond their hive.&lt;hpage&gt;That tribe has now long passed, and with them the secrets to their craft.&lt;page&gt;Ahhh. If they are gone, it&#8217;s a rarer piece than would be guessed! But what grand luck for this humble pinmaster to have worked with such a weapon!</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_GRAMAPHONE_NAME">Gramophone</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_SONGCLAVE_RETRY">&lt;page=T&gt;Good-goods for the pilgrims up high! Thems brave ones, settled up on that big-big Citadel.&lt;page=S&gt;These deliverings they will muchly need, miss courier. Carry them safe-safe, for us!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_FIX_DECLINE">Bzz-zzt! You hesitate! But your fear of my Extricator is born from mere ignorance, and you can overcome it with effort. Take a moment. Reconsider!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_REOFFER">The great Yarnaby can rid you of those nasty &#8220;roots&#8221;, but to crack your stiff shell my mighty Extricator needs an upgrade!</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_GENERIC">Hello again! Fancy buying something special before your tasks whisk you away?</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_MENTION_GOURMAND">&lt;hpage&gt;Couriers, I require a rasher of meat, for an old bug in the Citadel. Can you prepare it for me?&lt;page=T&gt;A bug up-up? Theys knows our finest food? If theys appreciate, we can prepare it most prompt! Miss courier has only to ask.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_DESK_DESC">A sturdy desk is the heart of any bellhome! Use it to take stock of your situation or organise your artefacts.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_FIX_REOFFER">These roots that torment you so... I&#8217;m not altogether familiar with them, but it matters not!&lt;page&gt;If there&#8217;s something inside a body that must come out, we use great Yarnaby&#8217;s Extricator! It&#8217;s your only hope, bzzt!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_DECLINE">You&#8217;d ask my aid, but won&#8217;t assist yourself? Then leave! Remain suffering, and stop being a bother to me, bzzt!</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_GENERIC_ACT3">Fellow resident! The world quakes and crumbles, but while my shell stays safe my shop stays open.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_COMPLETE_REFUSE">Welly, nay? You hold the precious oil for yourself? For what purpose do you deny a pinmaster their work? There is only I alive to work with such a wondrous substance!</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_REMEET_ACT3">What? What now? What&#8217;s all that great racket, what is it?&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, ma&#8217;am. It is only I. If you are disturbed by the rending of these lands, I fear some blame is mine to bear.&lt;page&gt;Blame, is it? Pah. Those who come after us can apportion blame as they see fit.&lt;page&gt;For now, my collection is the only thing that matters! I must protect it!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_MASKMAKER">&lt;page=S&gt;A delivery deadly, dangerous, fiercably cold, for old bug up there that does need it much-much! Serves us all he does, so we serve back.&lt;page=T&gt;And great test for you, miss courier! Most challenging-challenge this. The lacquer to bring is sloshy-slosh. A hard carry even for the best.&lt;hpage&gt;I have met this maker. His is a long service, worthy of respect. I will be glad to aid his efforts.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_PILGRIMSREST">&lt;page=S&gt;Deliverings for the waystation in the fields at Pharloom&#8217;s edge, a small rest-stop, still serving.&lt;page=S&gt;This journey is maybe not so very hard for you, miss courier? We think you is perfect for this wish!</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_REPEAT">Welcome, welcome, travellers all! Rest your weary shell and revive your flagging spirit!&lt;page&gt;Bellhart! Glorious, gleaming, and very very safe! Stay a while before you begin your final climb!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_MAGGOT_REPEAT">Go and rest! Bzzt! Free yourself of your trifling ailment and leave me in peace! The great Yarnaby has no time for petty maladies!&lt;hpage&gt;Very well, madam. I did not mean to waste your time.</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_MEET_EXPANDED">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, shopkeeper. It seems you&#8217;ve recovered well from that silken affliction.&lt;page&gt;Ah! Well, I&#8217;m a clever bug. When that strange thread struck down from above, I shut up tight and huddled in my bellhome.&lt;page&gt;Might&#8217;ve been a problem for the others about here, but my store was flush with supplies, so no fear I&#8217;d go hungry.&lt;hpage&gt;Your preparedness served you well then, and it seems your store is still well-stocked.&lt;page&gt;Oh yes, even my supplier is back to work, so I have plenty of goods to show you!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_4_PRE_REOFFER">Welly now! You have the oil, traveller! Allow me to bring about a shine bright as none before!</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_ASK_PROMPT_PLURAL">Give Relics?</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CONVO_2">But, hold! There is something more about you... I&#8217;ve sliced the shells of countless filthy pilgrims! All those plain, greying innards! Yours are something else entirely!&lt;page&gt;It tickles at my mind, still! Bzzt! What is it of your shell that eludes even my perfect, precise perception?&lt;page&gt;Would you show me, specimen? Go on! Let the great Yarnaby peer at your deeper, darker secrets!&lt;hpage&gt;I&#8217;ve no desire to see my shell pried into further, healer. Your service has succeeded, and taken its toll in pain. I hope only that I never again need to seek your aid.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_FURTHER_REPEAT">If ever upon your long road more oil is acquired, seek my service with haste! Who knows what form we could find deeper within your blade&#8217;s sharpened steel!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CLOSED_ACT3">Gahh! Who keeps making all that racket out there?! Such horrid shaking and screaming. The crucial work is being spoiled! Bzzzt!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_ENDED">The operation... a success! The simpletons hiding in that blasted bellvein would shudder into dust if they saw how much I achieve without them!&lt;hpage&gt;Madam... I shan&#8217;t lie, that was an ordeal such as I have rarely suffered...&lt;hpage&gt;And yet, the parasite does seem to have been... unbound somewhat. Whatever remnant still lingers in my shell feels calmed, enough for me to claim its power as my own.&lt;hpage&gt;Perhaps this is a fortunate result after all.&lt;page&gt;Of course. Of course! Great Yarnaby has healed you! Shout it through the caverns, scream it from the great spinning towers!&lt;page&gt;Just make sure they hear you in the so-called &#8216;civilised&#8217; settlements of this ignorant land!</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_POSTWINDOW_COMPLETE_REPEAT">A mighty collection of the past, is it not? If only I could hoard all of history here with me!</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_MEET_ACT3">Fellow resident, welcome home! The world may quake and crumble, and threaten its end, but while my shell stays safe my shop stays open.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CURSE_FIX_ACCEPT">Yes... yes! Bzzt! Finally, a specimen worthy of my mighty Extricator! My beautiful, unfairly-maligned Extricator! Come this way, bzzt...</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_BELLTOWN_MEET_OFFER_ALT">By claw! Who is this bold warrior, standing so calm and cool on entrance to Plinney&#8217;s bellhome!&lt;hpage&gt;Merely a traveller, sir, though one whose blade could benefit from your service.&lt;page&gt;Your blade! Of course, fierce warrior! Any fine pinmaster would detect the sign of deadly work upon that needle&#8217;s edge.&lt;page&gt;If your weapon sharpened would see our lands that much safer, then honour decrees it receives my care this very moment! What&#8217;s say I take a look?&lt;hpage&gt;</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CLOSED_QUEST">Come back with those spines, or not at all! The great Yarnaby&#8217;s time is precious, bzzt! I will not be distracted from my work!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_SAVED_TALK">Ahh... how welly romantic t&#8217;would&#8217;ve been, had the lost pilgrims struck me down beside her grave, to lie together forever as the world crumbles all &#8216;round...&lt;page&gt;But fortune has claimed otherwise! And perhaps &#8216;tis best for this humble pinmaster to continue his trade a little longer. These uncertain times will bring much new work, I should think!</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_CURSED">What&#8217;s this... twitching inside of you? A slave within a slave! Given over your shell to grow something greater?&lt;hpage&gt;A parasite has made its home within me. It saps my energy, and I can not purge it with strength alone...&lt;page&gt;Grnk. Lie down and die then, for all I care. Allow that wriggling thing its chance at life.&lt;page&gt;Or else... hff. Go seek the one exiled from Bellhart, little Yarnaby. She was chased out, high up into the moors, last I heard.</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_POSTWINDOW_FIRST">More, then! Bring me more relics of the past! Records, seals, idols! Let&#8217;s gather up the history of the world and hoard it all here, nice and safe!&lt;hpage&gt;If I happen upon more curiosities of this kingdom&#8217;s past, I may visit again. Until that time, keep yourself safe.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_MASKMAKER_RETRY">&lt;page=T&gt;More for you, miss courier! Lacquer, filled fresh, for the maker on the mount. We have much, so don&#8217;t worry for our supply. &lt;page=S&gt;To climb the frozen peak, it is a journey most difficult! Our thanks go full with you that tries again!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_GOURMAND_RETRY">&lt;page=T&gt;More meats for you, miss courier! Best you be delivering it swiftly quick! If left not stored, our rasher&#8217;s flavour fast turns foul.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_CLOSED_REPEAT">Shoo I say! Unless you&#8217;ve brought a worthy specimen, with something truly nasty inside them, bzzt! Otherwise, leave the great Yarnaby in peace!</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_PAINT_DESC">You&#8217;ve a good solid bell up there, though its surface is showing its age. Why not have us paint it fresh? A protective coat and a little flair!</entry>
<entry name="FISHER_DLG_MEET">&lt;hpage&gt;You seem hard at work, good bug. Are you a hunter, of a sort?&lt;page&gt;Of a simple sort, aye. I&#8217;m a pondcatcher around these parts. The last remaining, in fact! &lt;page&gt;Us few Bellharters are badly needing for fresh food, so my lone shell&#8217;s carrying quite the responsibility.&lt;page&gt;At least Shellwood Pond&#8217;s still full of good meat, &#8216;specially if your aim with a longpin&#8217;s as good as mine.</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_SNARE_REPEAT">My part&#8217;s been given, slave. We&#8217;ve no more need to speak.&lt;page&gt;Go and spin your spider&#8217;s web. Allow our kingdom&#8217;s restless soul its chance to blaze.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_3_PRE">&lt;hpage&gt;I have more oil, pinmaster. Its acquisition was no small task, but if it aids my blade, those challenges will be well rewarded.&lt;page&gt;Even more oil? What preposterous luck! That unseen gift, in quantity unheard, discovered by a single bug!&lt;page&gt;Would you pass the oil, traveller, and perhaps a few rosaries for the ongoing effort? Allow this pinmaster to again work wonder upon your blade?</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_CRESTSOCKET_BELLHART">An exquisite item, containing a cherished memory. I have an excellent memory myself, but I&#8217;m sure you can make good use of it.</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_SLAP_INTRO">Don&#8217;t act the fool, specimen! Bzzt! Share more of yourself, that I may gain greater understanding! Learning! What other hope is there to save our blighted, thankless world?! &lt;hpage&gt;I have declined, bug. Whatever you seek, you shall not find it either upon or within my shell.</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_HOUSE_FULL_TALK">&lt;page&gt;Miss traveller! Thanks to your valiant contributions, our little town&#8217;s starting to feel like its old self again. Homes have been hoisted, and the square shines!&lt;hpage&gt;I have seen the changes myself, Pavo. It is pleasing to hear my contributions have not been in vain. &lt;page&gt;Indeed! Your generosity is a guide for others! We&#8217;ve only one thing now sorely missing...&lt;page&gt;Bugs! What is a town without its residents? Age, scarcity, deadly thread... Bellhart is beset by endless ills. Now there&#8217;s just us remaining few as you&#8217;ve met.&lt;page&gt;In recognition of your noble efforts, and as one small step to solving the problem, I have decreed a grand gift should be given! A bellhome of your very own!&lt;page&gt;A place to reflect. A bed to lay in. It&#8217;s hanging up there at the top, beside our good pinmaster. &lt;hpage&gt;I have no plans to settle, Pavo, but for now my task in Pharloom remains, and while it does, a residence may prove useful.&lt;page&gt;Of course! Of course! Your fortitude inspires us all! And if trouble ever descends anew, it surely won&#8217;t hurt to have a resident warrior close at claw!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_REPEAT">If you refuse to share your secrets, then distract me no more, specimen! Bzzt!&lt;page&gt;There is still much work ahead for the great Yarnaby! Much thought, much learning!&lt;page&gt;Though the ungrateful world shuns me, still, by my own claws shall it be saved!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_SAVED_THANK_1">Welly&#8217;o! What a fearful fright you&#8217;ve saved poor Plinney from! Such a delight, at longest last, to see that fine needle dance and sing!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_4_PRE">&lt;hpage&gt;Again, pinmaster, I must ask your skilled service. I bring another gland of oil.&lt;page&gt;Oil, so much! This bug is past surprise! It is time methinks, to see your blade&#8217;s work finished! To bring about a shine bright as none before!&lt;page&gt;Welly now! Why wait? Would you have me begin, traveller?</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_SAVED_THANK_2">&lt;hpage&gt;These are deadly roads to wander, pinmaster, especially with the black soaked threads tearing the lands apart.&lt;hpage&gt;Your greatest chance for safety lies in Bellhart, with your fellows. You can protect one another, and perhaps in time rebuild.&lt;page&gt;Oh yes, of course! T&#8217;was not Plinney&#8217;s wish to abandon his dear bellfriends, but with the world now ending, I had to come and say one last farewell to my sweet Melatolla.&lt;page&gt;I should be returning though, quite rightly. Our town will be needing a pinmaster&#8217;s fine work now more than ever!</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_POSTWINDOW_COMPLETE">Yes... yes. This is a mighty collection indeed!&lt;page&gt;So many relics safely piled up in here, nice and safe! I&#8217;ve done so well to gather it all up!&lt;hpage&gt;If your collection pleases you, some acknowledgement of my own contribution to its growth is not undue.&lt;page&gt;Pah! Is it gratitude you seek?&lt;page&gt;I will allow you to keep viewing my collection. That is gratitude enough for what little you&#8217;ve given me!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_BONETOWNFIXER">&lt;page=S&gt;Once was common, this delivery, for the bugs in their camp beside the bone. Now even this is-is challenge.&lt;page=T&gt;Down there at base, where many pilgrims&#8217; journey start. To ready for their climb, these deliverings will give much value.</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_3_PRE_REOFFER">Would you pass the oil, traveller, and perhaps a few rosaries for their ongoing effort? Allow this pinmaster to again work wonder upon your blade?</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_TROPHYCAB_DESC">Found some fancy trophies on your travels? Then you&#8217;ll be needing these shelves to show them off!</entry>
<entry name="FISHER_DLG_04">Just passing through these lands, are you miss? I&#8217;d warn you not to stray far from Bellhart, but you&#8217;ve the look of one who can manage themself.</entry>
<entry name="FISHER_DLG_05">If you&#8217;re heading out across the pond, be wary of the other catchers. They&#8217;re all long lost to Pharloom&#8217;s Haunting.&lt;page&gt;Weak minds, the lotta them. Still, their longpins remain sharp enough.</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_HOUSE">Well, well! Welcome to you, our newest resident! I hope you&#8217;re finding your new home to your taste.&lt;hpage&gt;It is a finely forged bell, madam. I am fortunate to have a safe space to rest, even if my stay here may be short.&lt;page&gt;However long you&#8217;re with us, I&#8217;ve been holding onto some fine goods that&#8217;ll cozy up your home. This stuff ain&#8217;t for the riff-raff winding through, but a fellow Bellharter deserves the finest! </entry>
<entry name="GREETER_MEET">Welcome, welcome, weary pilgrim! Though glorious Bellhart may be past its finest shine, it still remains the last friendly stop before the Citadel. &lt;page&gt;It is the task of I, fair Pavo, to extend the warmest of welcome to those passing devout, such as your good self!&lt;hpage&gt;Your town seems returned to healthy form, good bug. I had some concern that, upon cutting you free, I&#8217;d find only husks.&lt;page&gt;Yes, well, many ahh... err... most of our residents did not fare so well... Still, it&#8217;s no good to dwell on dark things! We shall build, and grow, and welcome! As is any good bellbug&#8217;s task.</entry>
<entry name="FISHER_DLG_01">You&#8217;ve met Frey, miss? She&#8217;s usually stocking useful items for travellers such as yourself.</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_PAINT_PRE">The perfect choice! Your bell&#8217;s about to be looking the finest in town. We&#8217;ll get the work started straight away.</entry>
<entry name="GREETER_FURNISHINGS">If you&#8217;re ever finding that bellhome a little bare, make sure to speak with Frey. She&#8217;s been known to gather all sorts of fancy furnishings.&lt;page&gt;That stock&#8217;s useless for a passing pilgrim, but for a new resident its just the stuff to turn a bell into home.</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHOP_BEGIN_SONGCLAVE">&lt;page=S&gt;Up-up, in the big Citadel, a new place we heard is now claimed safety-safe! Theys too needing our deliverings, we is sure!&lt;page=T&gt;That Citadel. We knows its truths! Not so nicely-nice as pilgrims tells! Even if brave bugs would settle, danger still is close!&lt;page=S&gt;They would need deliverings, for food, for healings, for protection. Please takes them, miss courier!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_COMPLETE_ACCEPT">Tarano! We shall work, now as never. What joy you grant this humble artisan, traveller. Let us seek that shine thought lost within these lands...</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_ALREADY_GOT">&lt;page&gt;Welly, ho! That oil! You have it! That rare substance, hoarded close by the Citadel. Few are the pinmasters of our age that ever chanced to work its wonders.&lt;page&gt;Would you see it, traveller? The finest work of this fair pinmaster and your blade sharper still! Pass me the oil and we can commence!</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_TROPHYCAB_NAME">Memento Shelf</entry>
<entry name="RELIC_DEALER_ASK_PROMPT">Give Relic?</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_UPGRADE_REOFFER">Welly, yay? Reconsider my offer? Your blade would gleam at my fine skill!</entry>
<entry name="DOCTOR_MAGGOT">&lt;hpage&gt;Madam, I am sickly. Maggots of the fetid bogs beyond the moors writhe upon my shell. I would ask your aid in removing them.&lt;page&gt;Maggots! That&#8217;s all you bring the great Yarnaby?! My time is precious! Only for the seriously afflicted! The truly, hideously enfeebled. Bzzt!&lt;page&gt;Find a bench, or a bed, or a rock! It&#8217;s only rest you need. Settle yourself somewhere, and those maggots will soon wriggle themselves out of your shell. </entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_GENERIC_HOUSE">Welcome, fellow resident! Can I interest you in something special before you&#8217;re away again on your travels?</entry>
<entry name="SHOPKEEP_MEET">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, shopkeeper. It seems you&#8217;ve recovered well from that silken affliction.&lt;page&gt;Ah! Well, I&#8217;m a clever bug. When that strange thread struck down from above, I shut up tight and huddled in my bellhome.&lt;page&gt;Might&#8217;ve been a problem for the others about here, but my store was flush with supplies, so no fear I&#8217;d go hungry.&lt;hpage&gt;Your preparedness served you well then. Although... your store now seems quite bare.&lt;page&gt;Ahem. Yes. I&#8217;ll admit, the wait was longer than I&#8217;d anticipated, and a bug has to eat...&lt;page&gt;I&#8217;ll have more to offer you once my courier turns up. No doubt he&#8217;s been avoiding Bellhart since the curse set its sights on us.</entry>
<entry name="SHOP_ITEM_FURNISHING_LIGHTS_NAME">Gleamlights</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_ENSLAVED_1">You bother me again? Begone, I said!&lt;hpage&gt;I ask only if you know what has happened to the bugs above us. They hang trapped in a vast snare of thread.&lt;page&gt;Hff. Hardly surprising. That there&#8217;s the final fate for all in Pharloom. Just come seeking a little sooner for them above.&lt;page&gt;Surely, oh surely, you don&#8217;t imagine your own end will be different? All that hunger, and fear, and pride, filling your fragile heart. You too are bound to end ensnared!&lt;page&gt;Grnk! Begone. In Pharloom, only a fool believes themselves free.</entry>
<entry name="BELLHERMIT_ENSLAVED_2">You want to cut them down? Hff. Yes, you look cruel enough.&lt;page&gt;Once the strings are cut, pain will return to them. They will remember fear and longing.&lt;page&gt;What a choice you make for them! Such power you grant yourself!</entry>
<entry name="PINSMITH_QUEST_CANCOMPLETE">&lt;hpage&gt;Pinmaster, I have acquired oil with which my needle may see further sharpening.&lt;page&gt;Bonva! What wonder? What wish? To steal a gift so fine. Few are the pinmasters of our age that ever worked with such a substance.</entry>
</entries>
