<entries>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_MEET_PT2">&lt;page=S&gt;You seem displeased, Old One. We only did as you asked, yes? The snare is sprung, the creature consumed.&lt;hpage&gt;You bound it to that void!&lt;page=S&gt;Don&#8217;t play daft. You should well know our family&#8217;s fixations. Surely you had a hunch?&lt;page=B&gt;How else could we hope to trap one of your pale kin? Or see her consumed with such insatiable efficiency?&lt;hpage&gt;Then you have miscalculated, gravely. The white knight, she fell with the mother...&lt;page=M&gt;Oh ho... The quakes, yes? We have felt their force, even here. So the mother resists the dark... to save the child?&lt;hpage&gt;That is my guess. I must descend to the void below, and see clear that truth for myself.&lt;page=M&gt;Ohhhh. How… unfortunate. All of Pharloom will fall to her flailing.&lt;hpage&gt;So it may, but I will not watch idle while it crumbles.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_TOOL_METAL">This lump here is well heavy, and shiny too, so it&#8217;s surely worth somethin&#8217;!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SHOP_REPEAT_ACT3">Desperate times make for desperate customers, heh heh! So let&#8217;s get to tradin&#8217;, eh?</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_HERO_WIN_PRE_2">Again... Huu... Huu. Truly incredible!&lt;page&gt;Was it the course? Did I lose focus? Or are you simply the bug I have waited so long for? Her of such skill that my wish could, at last, be granted?&lt;page&gt;Another reward must be given for your speed, nimble bug. One deserved in full!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_HINT_ZANGO">Have you heard, miss grown-up? Beyond the moss, in the crumbled caverns filled with worms, much change is happening, different to the horrid, stretching dark outside.&lt;page&gt;What brings such bright and bold transformation? Is it a beast? Or a bug unseen? How wondrous it would be to discover them, hidden away in some deep corner!&lt;page&gt;You must go searching, miss grown-up! You and that sharp, sharp blade. Think of the strange and succulent shell waiting to be added to your journal?</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BELLHART_MEET">Now, isn&#8217;t this a wondrous place! Golden bells, for weary shells! Ha ha ha!&lt;hpage&gt;This settlement offers safety now, little pilgrim. Perhaps you should make a home here?&lt;hpage&gt;You&#8217;ve done well to make it this far, and the roads ahead will only be more dangerous.&lt;page&gt;Oh, dangerous they surely are! But I will gladly tread any path that holds wonders as magnificent as this, red maiden!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MEET_BONE_1C">&lt;hpage&gt;You have keen sight for my skill, bug, but my childhood has long since passed. What has happened here? I see signs of battle all around.</entry>
<entry name="HORNET_SILENCE">&lt;hpage&gt;...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_WHITE_FLOWER_ACT3">&lt;hpage&gt;The time is close, Shakra. The cost was grave, and the challenge steep, but I have claimed a power that can put end to this disaster. &lt;page&gt;Gendaa... This is good, Hornet Wielding Needle, essential. My own strength has near reached its limit, and the dark husks continue their assault unceasing.&lt;page&gt;Take your final action, and let us all see the end of this.</entry>
<entry name="SETH_FESTIVAL_REPEAT_POST_MEMENTO">Your achievements in the games are inspiring! In time, I may have to challenge those impressive scores...</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;Good luck on your quest Garmond. If you hope to claim justice for your fellows passed, I suspect you&#8217;ve some challenge yet ahead.&lt;page&gt;Aye! Zaza and I&#8217;ll fight to cavern&#8217;s end if it need be, for the bugs held in our hearts, and our honour as knights!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_AID_MEET_FORUM">Ahh, can you feel it too? The thralls of the Citadel are gathered close, in overwhelming numbers!&lt;page&gt;Together though, the three of us would be more overwhelming still! Would you allow us to fight by your side, brave sister?</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_CITADEL_MEET">Well, well! See what happens to nasty bully-bugs when they come after poor old Grindle? That&#8217;s a well-deserved end, we reckon.&lt;page&gt;We heard this old Sitty-dell was nice and quiet and burstin&#8217; with goodies. So what&#8217;s happened, eh? Why&#8217;s it crawlin&#8217; with bullies and busybodies?&lt;hpage&gt;The creature that haunts this place is stirring, little thief. The Citadel&#8217;s caste now roam the halls. You would do well to leave soon, if you mean to survive.&lt;page&gt;What what? You bein&#8217; mirthful? We&#8217;re stayin&#8217; here &#8216;til we&#8217;re done pilfering! You should be the one leavin&#8217; if you&#8217;re so afeared!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_HINT_VOLTNEST">High up, above the caverns all of crust, Nuu has been told of a hole, filled with writhing things, all zipping and zapping.&lt;page&gt;But so sad! Nuu cannot herself see it. The lands quake and rattle. The savage threads stretch. The dangers are too much.&lt;page&gt;It must be you, miss grown-up, older, stiffer, a shell less precious. Seek the cave, and the things within. How else will the journal be complete?</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_ZAPNEST_MEET">Ahh miss grown-up, Nuu hoped you would return here. For clever Nuu can track well where you have been, she sees your cut-marks and sniffs out your fragrant trail!&lt;page&gt;And look where the trail has led sweet Nuu! A thick wriggler lived in this nest, rumbling and crackling in the darkness.&lt;page&gt;Its sour juices still line these rocky insides, and patient Nuu will gather it all up!&lt;hpage&gt;There is much to learn in these crusted highlands Nuu, but much danger as well. Indulge your curiosity if you must, but keep your senses trained on the darkness.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_HERO_LOSE">Don&#8217;t let defeat weigh on you, nimble bug! If strength remains, simply step again to the challenge. Let us soar swift together!</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHORT_THANK_PT1">Oh! Those horrible beasty-beasts are gone! Much and many thanks for you, mighty warrior!&lt;hpage&gt;It was a simple thing, small bug. I assume you are Tipp, the courier?&lt;hpage&gt;Frey, the Bellhart trader, seemed concerned for your safety... and for the cargo you carry.&lt;page&gt;She sent you?! Bah! She needs to learny-learn a little patience! I&#8217;m is barely been away! But still... is lucky-lucky for me you came.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_CORALCAVERNS_NAME">Sands of Karak Map</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_SHORT_THANK_PT2">Well, I&#8217;m is be off now. That old grubly-grub in the bell will come after me herself if she not get her goods!</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_HERO_WIN_AFTER_WISH_REPEAT">Now I must train, and strive, further and faster by your example. Your skill upon these tracks has roused my spirit, nimble bug. You shall forever have my thanks.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_BELLHART_DESC">A town built within the thick vein of bells that runs through Pharloom&#8217;s core. One wonders who would craft so many, and for what purpose?</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_SPAR_INTRO">Hornet Wielding Needle! With my master&#8217;s passing, I have resolved to improve my skills that, in time, I may match her prime.&lt;page&gt;Much work I must do to achieve that goal. I have found this wide bare stone fine ground on which to train.&lt;page&gt;Would you spar with me now? Raise that blade and test my rings! You may prove my greatest challenge yet.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MAPPING">&lt;hpage&gt;Your charts and tools show fine skill, Shakra. I&#8217;ve met few who&#8217;d match your talent.&lt;page&gt;Cartography! Peh. Bakallo! It is a craft-skill common amongst my tribe. Most important to keep one&#8217;s mind sharp when on a journey.&lt;page&gt;The charting of caverns, the memory of travel, the knowing of one&#8217;s place within the kingdom, an engaging task for a warrior&#8217;s mind.&lt;page&gt;An unfortunate thing that my great mentor never learnt the skill. Her talent at getting lost... I should almost be impressed...</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SLAB_REPEAT">Lots of good stuff tucked away in this old prison... lovely place to bring a lucky little snitchbug like Grindle! What a favour those lugs did us! O-hoho!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_DECLINED_ACT3">Oooh, ma. Miss grown-up, you deny poor Nuu? So sour!&lt;hpage&gt;I am sorry, Nuu. Though I recognise the value in your wish, my own task is too pressing. </entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_GREET">Come to rest here, miss grown-up? Then let Nuu see our journal, for she is eager to see your cuts!</entry>
<entry name="SETH_CITADEL_MEET">This great structure... It would have taken the lifetimes of so many bugs to build it. Now its wounds run deep, and I can hear the groaning of its final breaths.&lt;page&gt;Everything that grows must pass, I suppose. Still, to witness even its current state is a privilege I&#8217;ll not squander.&lt;page&gt;And what of you, friend Hornet? Where are your travels taking you?&lt;hpage&gt;They have taken me deep, and will take me yet deeper still. I have a responsibility to cut this land free of its dark fate.&lt;hpage&gt;That is no concern of yours though, sir. You should continue your own journey, albeit with a claw on your weapon at all times.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_MEET_B">To our safe haven? Our home... This is what&#8217;s left of it after the great breaking began.&lt;page&gt;There was that terrible noise from above. Everything shook and fell apart, and the black threads sprung up from beneath. Many a poor pilgrim has already been lost to the destruction.&lt;page&gt;You might have been too, if not for some fleeing pilgrims who found you fallen and carried you back to us.&lt;hpage&gt;The black threads... I may understand their source.&lt;hpage&gt;I must speak with the old Caretaker. Do you know what has become of him? I see he has left you his garb.&lt;page&gt;Oh, yes. He charged me with looking after those remaining here, said he had to confer with his family down below.&lt;hpage&gt;Down below... Then they have slunk away to hide in their ruined chapel.&lt;hpage&gt;I must pay them a visit. Thank you, Sherma. Stay safe, and take care of your fellow pilgrims.</entry>
<entry name="SHAKRA_GRAND_FORUM">Bakkana! A battle well won! The haunted bugs have been defeated and the way forward is yours. Let us meet again soon, away from this dreadful Citadel.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_JUDGESTEPS_DESC">Huge caves ascending to Pharloom&#8217;s Citadel. The roads are slowly being devoured by sand and howling wind.</entry>
<entry name="G_PRINCE_SONG_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;Farewell, tall bug, until we cross again.&lt;page&gt;Or until death calmly claims us both...</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_EXTRA_WIN_PRE">Again and again you prove your mastery, nimble bug, yet still I never tire of the challenge!&lt;page&gt;As reward for such an impressive feat of endurance, I have only this small trophy, a memento given by my own speed teacher, now fairly passed to you.</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_DEEP_MEMORY_REPEAT">&lt;page=S&gt;Bring us the hearts, Old One. Make&#8217;em beat, fierce and final. See for yourself the forgotten strength of this land of bugs before we burn those memories in its saving.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_CITADEL_MEET2">Tch... Hahahaa. Marvelous! So the spider knows something of fathomless beings, and still it hopes to stand against one, a god... &lt;page&gt;Where do you hide this boundless strength you claim, spider? I&#8217;ve watched your struggle towards us. Yours was a painful, broken trek. One needs grace to stand before the divine.&lt;hpage&gt;Then best you keep watching, child. I&#8217;ve found those who claim themselves a god can rarely match the title.&lt;hpage&gt;And experience tells me, even gods can fall.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_WILDS">&lt;hpage&gt;Shakra, you look well at home in these wilds.&lt;page&gt;Poshanka! These scorched fields offer many paths and much combat. To leap from vantage upon the red-shells or to meet them face-front with rings ready? These are decisions to live for!&lt;page&gt;I am much surprised those soft pilgrims ever safely climbed this scorched and savage place.</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_STAG_REPEAT">Here, the proof of our majesty... mark of our divine right...</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_OFFER_1">Hoi hoi! A nimble opponent appears. At last! At last!&lt;hpage&gt;If you are seeking challengers, sir, you should choose a location less far afield. It is rare chance I, or any bug, would come upon this distant cavern.&lt;page&gt;True! Though once discovered, could there be a more perfect spot? This giant, boney body, so distant from Pharloom&#8217;s ails.&lt;page&gt;Here, freely, we can test our speed and our sleek shells. Here we may race!&lt;page&gt;You must be eager to step to the task, challenger? Fulfil my wish! Let us discover our limits together! </entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_UNFINISHED_MEET">Our capital, built grand... The seat of our sovereignty... slipped from my mind...&lt;page&gt;Why does it fade? Why can I not recall that sacred place?</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_ENCLAVE_REPEAT">Zaza and I will tarry here a little longer... These pilgrims need watching over, and we are committed to the task.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_MEET_4_BRIDGE">Delicious! I like you already!&lt;page&gt;But what a bore it would be to cut you down now, when you&#8217;re so achingly close to our grand Citadel...&lt;page&gt;Climb higher, little spider. I want to savour your struggle just a little longer!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_ZAPNEST_SLAP3">But Nuu is sensible, she understands. Miss grown-up has purpose, she must be away.&lt;page&gt;The cleaning can wait for another time. Nuu is patient... always patient.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SLAB_2">&lt;hpage&gt;You seem to have some familiarity with this prison and its guards. Do you know a path to escape?&lt;page&gt;Escape! A little jailbug like you ain&#8217;t ever escapin&#8217; anything! Get out of here, will you? Stop bothering us! You got nothing to steal, so we got nothing to talk about!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_DEFEATED_REPEAT">Though the dust has not yet settled over our battle here, Zaza and I must soon be away. The memory of our village calls us ever onward. Farewell, brave sister!</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_OFFER_4">&lt;page&gt;You would challenge again, nimble bug? You have proven yourself time and again.&lt;hpage&gt;Your course can still provide understanding, sir. Upon it, I see my own limits clearer and learn to push them further. &lt;page&gt;Of course! Of course! And I can learn much following behind your fair form.&lt;page&gt;I&#8217;d need only a moment, and the track would again be ready. </entry>
<entry name="LACE_MEET_3">&lt;hpage&gt;Your threats are worthless, child. If you are my foe, stay your voice and raise your blade.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_MEET_2">I can save you, little spider. All the trouble you&#8217;d face above. All the suffering. It&#8217;s so simple.&lt;page&gt;I&#8217;ll just skewer you here and now, pluck that flickering life right out of you.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_MEET_1">How sad. A little spider has fallen from its cage. So lost. So weak. Poor little morsel.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_RESULT_1">Ooooh ma, is well-begun. Many creatures have been recorded, but many many more still to be learned of!&lt;page&gt;Miss grown-up, you should rest quick and venture out to hunt again soon, thinks Nuu!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_DEFEATED_GNAT">Well fought sister, well fought! Though terrible and tenacious, the beast was no match for us.&lt;page&gt;Be proud! The bugs of this land will sing of our victory to their offspring, and their offspring&#8217;s offspring, forever more!</entry>
<entry name="LACE_TOWER_DEFEAT_1">Hah... aha ha ha ha ha!&lt;page&gt;Congratulations, spider. Finally, I felt your sting, and you&#8217;ve bared the truth of my pathetic empty shell.&lt;hpage&gt;You always had the scent, child. You are no bug. Yours is a life born entirely from thread.&lt;page&gt;Life? You&#8217;re too generous! This weak, wasting existence. This was not life, just a husk shaped to act as a child.&lt;hpage&gt;Yours was life, pale one. Do not confuse your unique creation with its absence. I have seen others make the same mistake.&lt;page&gt;Platitudes, spider? From you? Don&#8217;t be gross.&lt;page&gt;Head on. Climb up, up and away. You&#8217;ve earned your audience with the divine.&lt;page&gt;Face the holy mother who would fashion so cruel and crude a daughter as me.</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_REPEAT">Conversing is a pleasure, but I must return to my observance. Try not to leave too much of a trail when you leave, please.</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_DESCEND_REPEAT">&lt;page=M&gt;Enough chatting, Old One. Best you get heading below. Whatever action you&#8217;re planning, time is against you.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MASTER_ITEM">For sharing this moment I shall have you accept a gift, one I had believed I would never pass. &lt;page&gt;You would take these rings, and the learnings to make more.&lt;page&gt;They are built of a clever method devised by my master and will crush hard this kingdom&#8217;s toughest shell. Use them, and she is remembered!&lt;hpage&gt;My thanks, Shakra. To gain a tool so defined by its owner, I am much grateful. They shall prove a great aid on my own journey.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_SKULLKING_REPEAT">The warmth of these caverns keeps many smells alive! Is good for Nuu, who is always searching carefully for learnings!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CITADEL_SPA_NOENCLAVE">&lt;hpage&gt;Little pilgrim, these baths provide some respite from the dangers without, but even so you should not let down your guard.&lt;hpage&gt;You must have seen now that the bugs of this Citadel are long fallen to the Haunting.&lt;page&gt;Ahh... some of my brothers and sisters have seemed... lost somehow, yes. But to be lost is to be sometime found, is it not sung?&lt;page&gt;Yes... The Citadel will provide for them. It is a holy place indeed, that holds wonders such as this lovely warm bath!</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_ACCEPT_SHORT">Hoi! Let our mighty contest of shells commence again!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SLAB_MEET">Hoy! We thought one of them buzzing bullies was sneakin&#8217; up on us, but it&#8217;s just a mangy jailbug!&lt;page&gt;Why you in here, then? Caught thievin&#8217; were you? Greedy, greedy!&lt;hpage&gt;I&#8217;ve stolen nothing. Rather, I suspect the wardens are servants of the Citadel. The cage used in my capture bore similar runes to the one that first brought me to this land.&lt;hpage&gt;Bound in that cage, I&#8217;d have proved a fine gift were they to deliver me to their masters.&lt;page&gt;Pah, there ain&#8217;t nothin&#8217; fine about you, jailbug. We recognised a fellow thief soon as we saw you!&lt;page&gt;Now, don&#8217;t be lingerin&#8217; around here. Those guards&#8217;ll be wanting to pop you back in your cage quick quick!&lt;hpage&gt;They&#8217;ll not get the chance. I will reclaim my belongings and leave this grim place with haste.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_SPAR_DEFEAT">You recover quickly. Already, my ring-marks have faded from your shell. If you are prepared, let us duel again.</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC4">...Yes, communication is the heart of it. The grandest boasts and the tiniest murmurings all have their meanings...&lt;page&gt;...Your point is well made. Even the flowers have their stories to tell. Light can be cast anywhere...&lt;hpage&gt;I&#8217;ve no desire to interrupt your meditations, Herald, but I am eager to speak with you, if you would listen...&lt;page&gt;...Take note of it all, render it in line, you&#8217;ll be glad that you did. You can take the journey home with you...</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_COMPLETION_RESULT_2">Oooh, but the scroll is so heavy with beautiful beasts! Could it be that the works is almost complete? Miss grown-up, you must keep your preyings up. No time for rest!</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_ENTRY_MEET">The myth we made... by grace... by blade...&lt;page&gt;All bowed before we princes green...</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_LAKE_REPEAT">So many moments spent simple... joyful... free...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_DUSTPENS_BROKENBENCH">Do you see? How crass and frail that Citadel&#8217;s machines! This one groans in pain at its very existence.&lt;hpage&gt;Its mechanism is likely jammed. If the gears were unstuck its clamorous complaints would soon cease, and it could become a useful place to rest.&lt;page&gt;A place to rest or no, I desire only for the noise to stop!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_SHELLWOOD">These root-woven roads show evidence of my master&#8217;s passage. A thrice-crushed bug, gouged wood, score-prints of sharp claws passing. Small signs that only I can read.&lt;page&gt;Though the trail is cold, it eases me to know she is still within this land.</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_INTRODUCE">&lt;hpage&gt;These are dangerous fields, young one, not for casual wandering. What task sees you brave them?&lt;page&gt;A treacherous quest! But a crucial one! Upon the last wish of my father, I&#8217;ve taken up the study of these wild caves.&lt;page&gt;These fields still display life and growth, even as the lands around erode to dust.&lt;page&gt;There is a hot harmony here that eludes the grey wastes above and the dry Marrow beside. With time and study, I shall uncover why.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_TOOL_COMPASS_DESC">Track your location throughout these winding lands with a bone compass. Each member of our tribe can craft them. I would pass you mine, for a small price. </entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_COMPLETION_RESULT_1">Ooooh, ma ma! Even young Nuu never guessed that Pharloom held so many fascinating creatures! Soft ones, hard ones, small ones, big ones! Nuu is greedy to see what remains!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_NOBENCH">You see this idol before us, red maiden? I have passed its like before. They mark our pilgrimage well.&lt;page&gt;If we sing to it, a miraculous shrine will rise from the ground, and we will have a place to rest! Such a wonder!&lt;hpage&gt;It is not song that rouses this shrine, but payment in rosaries.&lt;hpage&gt;Without rosaries, the shrine remains hidden. I have encountered similar constructs on Pharloom&#8217;s paths. This kingdom does not grant rest lightly.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_E_DESC">You can use these to mark places of importance or reminders on your map.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These I have fashioned from the husks of old bells. A hard task to make, so the cost reflects the extra effort.</entry>
<entry name="SHAKRA_AID_MEET_FORUM">Poshanka! Here we meet, high atop this twisted steel structure. I can sense fierce enemies ahead.&lt;page&gt;It seems you too draw closer to your trail&#8217;s end. With my own task now resolved, my rings call for combat.&lt;page&gt;Hornet Wielding Needle, shall we fight forward together?</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_HEALER_REPEAT">All of these marvellous healing supplies... Surely they, at least, are some proof of the Citadel&#8217;s holy nature?</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_RESCUE_MEET1">H-hoy red m-maiden! Have no f-fear, &#8216;tis only I, Sherma!&lt;page&gt;I found healing supplies, b-but then the way back collapsed... and I heard moaning from the dark... oh, how thankful I am to see you!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_CRAWL_NAME">Wormways Map</entry>
<entry name="SHAKRA_AID_REPEAT">Shall we fight forward together?</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_REPEAT">The great Citadel is so close, I can hear the voices of our brother and sister pilgrims calling out to us!</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_MEET_HUNTERCAMP">What a battle, brave warrior! You&#8217;re the first I&#8217;ve seen who could match the red-shells and emerge victorious.&lt;hpage&gt;They are deadly foes indeed, and seemingly keen hunters. You did well to keep yourself hidden from them, young bug.&lt;page&gt;I did, didn&#8217;t I? Disguise and subterfuge are skills I&#8217;ve honed keenly, all in aid of my most important work!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_MOORWING_INFORM">Mind yourself while you travel this grim land. A great winged beast has been stalking the heights, swooping without warning and tearing the life out of unwary travellers!&lt;hpage&gt;I believe I have seen the creature you speak of. It may have marked me as prey, and followed me down onto the lower roads of the moor.&lt;page&gt;What what! Gurrrooo! The beast has been spotted! Once Zaza has fully rested, we&#8217;ll set to tracking it down!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_HEALER_MEET">Welcome back red maiden, and thank you again for coming to my aid.&lt;page&gt;I&#8217;m no healer, but with the supplies we found in the ward below even my unlearned claws can ease the suffering of our brothers and sisters.&lt;page&gt;That such darkness could creep into this most holy of places, even though we pilgrims kept our promise to ascend...&lt;page&gt;I confess, I wonder at the meaning of it all. But enlightenment does not come easily, or all at once... I should just continue my task in the meantime.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_ENCLAVE_MEET1">Hrm...? Oh, hoy there! I was hoping we would meet here, red maiden.&lt;page&gt;Rising at last to the heights of the Citadel and being amongst so many of my brothers and sisters... it is a blessing indeed. Yes, a blessing.&lt;hpage&gt;Your voice belies some hesitation in that belief, little pilgrim. You have seen now the reality of this broken place. What do you make of it, truly?</entry>
<entry name="COURIER_TALL_THANK_PT1">Safely-saved is Pill! But who is this rare carer for the shell of another? Name yourself, good bug!&lt;hpage&gt;I am Hornet, Pill. Your brother wished for your return to Bellhart, where he waits now. I&#8217;m sure he will be eager to see you alive.&lt;page&gt;Young Tipp! How he worries always. Blessed I am for the care, him and you Miss Hornet! A lucky bug is me!</entry>
<entry name="DICE_PILGRIM_DEPLETED_REPEAT">I pray my dice bring you luck on your final climb, sister. And I pray that by parting with them, my own ascent shall be made lighter.</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_HUNTERQUEEN_STATUE">See here, this old statue. I&#8217;ve been thinking long on it, what clues it might hold.&lt;page&gt;The claw-work seems beyond the other structures throughout these caves. Who was she I wonder, to deserve such refined remembrance?&lt;hpage&gt;Hers is the form of a dancer, and the craft is indeed exquisite. There must once have been more to these ants, before the Haunting snared their shells and minds.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_COMPLETE_2">Uahhhhh... The forbidden taste...</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CITADEL_SPA_REPEAT">Holy water, nice and hot,&lt;br&gt;Makes a perfect swimming spot,&lt;br&gt;Heals your worries in a flash,&lt;br&gt;So jump on in... splash splash splash! Ha ha ha!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_ROSARY_MAGNET">Very, very lucky little trinket we got &#8216;ere! Pulls &#8216;em little clickie-clackies right into yer waitin&#8217; claws!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_MEET_CITADEL_FIRST">Gurrroo! A fellow warrior braves this blighted place! Know you stand before the honoured knight Garmond, and brave companion Zaza.&lt;page&gt;Together, Zaza and I are wish bound to scale this Citadel, and vanquish the horrors at its heart!&lt;hpage&gt;Then good luck to you, sir bug. It is heartening to meet another of sound mind and fortitude enough to fight back against the many haunted husks.&lt;page&gt;Aye! Never-ending, these unnatural opponents! This Citadel seems its twisted source, and honour decrees we must fight on, until we rend the heart of its decay!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_SHAMAN_CREST">&lt;hpage&gt;I found the well in the hidden chambers beyond. The power that remained at its base I have taken for myself.&lt;page=S&gt;Bound yourself a new nature, aye? And from the shells of our ancestors, no less, all those many who&#8217;ve called these lands their own.&lt;page=S&gt;You make it seem so simple-like. All o&#8217;that learning, all o&#8217;that strength... sucked up in a whirl of Silk.&lt;page=M&gt;We&#8217;d call you a thief, Old One, and cruel for the taking, but its all coming down soon if you can&#8217;t stop it.&lt;page=M&gt;If there&#8217;s advantage in your act that might see these caves safe, then it&#8217;s better you make your claim.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_BELLHART_REPEAT_ACT3">Best keep your visits brief, Hornet Wielding Needle. Without swift action taken, our world&#8217;s ruin seems certain.&lt;page&gt;If you cannot calm Pharloom&#8217;s tortured throes, then certainly no other bug could face the task. &lt;hpage&gt;As you say, Shakra. I shall do what I must.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_HINT_GREYWARRIOR">Near the edge of those lands swept by wind and sand, Nuu has seen it, a single bug, watching, waiting.&lt;page&gt; Too scared was Nuu to crawl close, for fear it would wake, and its big blade might mark this perfect shell.&lt;page&gt;For the journal&#8217;s sake, you should seek the bug, up on edge, through a tall tunnel hidden by crust.&lt;page&gt;A hard find, that one, but Nuu is not worried! She knows your adult cunning will see you there quick!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_NOSTOCK_ACT3">For my mapping stock, we have traded all the charts and tools I can provide. While this new threat remains, I shall not make more.&lt;page&gt;My cartography may be a simple sort, but I hope that my craft shared has made your travels easier.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_AID_READY">Lead on, sister! Zaza and I will be close behind!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BONEGATE_OPENED">Hoy! Did you see it, red maiden? The great gate heard my song and, in its infinite and ancient kindness, has opened the way forward for us!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_DEFEATED_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;Must you not press on, sirs?&lt;page&gt;Oh, yes! We will be off at once. Very soon. I fear though, that Zaza must rest a little longer...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MEET_BONE_1A">Poshanka! Edges sharp and senses keen!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_TALK2">&lt;page=M&gt;Even knowing her motivation, it is a shock the monarch can resist so long. We&#8217;d thought none could survive that void.&lt;hpage&gt;She will have retreated within her protective form, that cocoon of thread. Even as the dark eats its outer, she will spin its Silk anew.&lt;hpage&gt;The effort would be immense and it will strain her soul thin, but what other choice remains?&lt;hpage&gt;This is the desperate act of a dying god. A defiance that, left unchallenged, will bring your kingdom&#8217;s ruin. </entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_TALK1">&lt;page=M&gt;The quakes...This collapse will take Pharloom all.&lt;hpage&gt;If the void doesn&#8217;t claim it first. Surely you&#8217;ve seen them, the black threads that wrack your lands? The dark leeches up, possessed upon the fallen monarch&#8217;s Silk.&lt;hpage&gt;Pharloom&#8217;s roads were not safe before. Now they&#8217;ll prove impassable. Those pilgrims still alive in your lands best huddle and hope. &lt;hpage&gt;If there can be another end to this, it is up to us to discover it.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BONEGATE_MEET_2">&lt;hpage&gt;Why do you sing, little one? This bony gate seems like a poor audience.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_RESCUE_END2">&lt;hpage&gt;Can you safely make your way back to the settlement, little one? I could escort you if need be.&lt;page&gt;Oh no, I&#8217;ll lay no more of my troubles upon you, red maiden. With the way cleared I can return under my own guidance.&lt;page&gt;After all, what&#8217;s another pilgrimage, eh? Ha ha!&lt;page&gt;Oh! And I have something for you as well. I found it buried amongst the broken relics down here in the darkness, glowing with a pale light.&lt;page&gt;&#8217;Tis an odd-looking thing... not exactly holy-seeming... but I would be honoured if you accepted it all the same!</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_HERO_WIN_POST">The challenge! The course! It shall be improved. Yes! Yes! The truest test is still to come. We shall fly fast together once more!</entry>
<entry name="SETH_SHELLWOOD_REPEAT">I&#8217;ve learnt too that travelling is not without its dangers... but I find myself wielding my weapon quite adeptly.&lt;page&gt;It&#8217;s curious, the way our instincts can guide us with such precision.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_BELLHART_NAME">Bellhart Map</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_SPAR_VICTORY">Un-Daak... well struck. To face the fury of your weapon in a true battle would be an experience indeed. I would gladly duel again, if you have the time for it.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_GRAND_FORUM">Hoho sister, my whiskers are still quivering! That&#8217;s how you know you had a rousing battle!&lt;page&gt;You go on ahead. Zaza and I will keep guard here and catch any stragglers.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_MEET_A">Hoy, red maiden. &#8216;Tis a prayer answered to see you safely wake.&lt;hpage&gt;Little Sherma? What has happened here?</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_CALLED">Poshanka! So you found my calling ring, Child Wielding Needle. I recognised the sound of your weapon&#8217;s foreign metal against it.&lt;page&gt;On the hunt for my master, I am often away, but I still use this place as camp. Use the ring to call me whenever you wish to make trade.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_WILDS_NAME">Far Fields Map</entry>
<entry name="SHAKRA_AID_ACCEPT">&lt;hpage&gt;Gladly I will accept your aid Shakra. Let us cut closer to this Citadel&#8217;s haunted heart.&lt;page&gt;Garrok! Hornet Wielding Needle. Beside you, I will gladly raise my rings!</entry>
<entry name="G_PRINCE_SONG_MEET">I&#8217;d hoped to never step these hateful halls, yet here I stand, as all those hapless bugs before.&lt;hpage&gt;You&#8217;ve journeyed far from that damp cell, tall bug. If you would oppose the minions of this Citadel, you have my respect.&lt;page&gt;Hmph. Then we share a rare stance, warrior. Few others seem possessed of will enough to resist.&lt;page&gt;So many weak minds, drawn up and strung, in love with the great golden leech atop their lands.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_MEET">Ho there, brave sister! What poetry has fate writ, that we should meet here at the peak of this ghastly Citadel!&lt;page&gt;Beasts and fiends, all here are lost to that horrid Haunting! And out from this golden corpse it seeps to plague the good bugs of the land below. Well, no more we say!&lt;hpage&gt;You should beware brave sirs, the creature that commands this curse is a foe far beyond bug. I would not see your lives given in vain.&lt;page&gt;Pah! We beware nothing! We would give our lives a hundred times over to finally cut away the evil that clutches our kingdom!</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_MEET_HIDDEN">Goodness! This is just too embarrassing! Detected even through my perfect cover! What tell? What error? Surely something gave me away!&lt;hpage&gt;It was no one thing, young bug. Your disguise is near faultless. I&#8217;ve merely spent a long life being watchful.&lt;page&gt;Gah! Then I&#8217;ll just have to hope the beasts about don&#8217;t share such keen sight. It&#8217;ll be so much harder to accomplish my work if I&#8217;m detected, or eaten!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_PILGRIMSREST_REPEAT">Sister, sister, tired and glum,&lt;br&gt;We will sing, and you can hum,&lt;br&gt;Together we shall overcome!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_DEEP_MEMORY1">&lt;page=M&gt;Oh ho! Back from the depths with nary a scratch! Is it as you feared?&lt;hpage&gt;It is, and worse. Your snare has sunk the monarch deep, deeper than I can safely descend.&lt;hpage&gt;To cut Pharloom free, I must plunge below the surface of that lake of liquid nothing.&lt;page=B&gt; No shell survives submersion in that void, Old One, not even yours.&lt;hpage&gt;Not without aid, certainly. Though aid may exist. The flower that resists the dark. Do you know of it?&lt;page=M&gt;The Everbloom?... We&#8217;ve heard the tale, but had thought it a myth. If ever it sprouted in our lands we would surely have known?&lt;hpage&gt;I would not seek it in these lands. I need its power full, and it is too fragile to sustain here long. I would seek it in my memory.&lt;page=S&gt; Oh ho ho! So you&#8217;d have us wrench open your soul, to retrieve the fabled bloom? Can such a thing be done?&lt;hpage&gt;For another bug, no, but I am Weaver enough to attempt it.&lt;hpage&gt;In the distant past, I knew the flower. My thread still holds its faint memory. If the Everbloom was grasped strongly enough within my Silk, it could be made to manifest.&lt;page=M&gt;Ah! So you&#8217;re asking another spell of us? To reveal the flower clear?... But to illuminate one of your kind&#8217;s old memories, so acutely... This is no easy thing, even for us...&lt;page=M&gt;Old One, you must give us a moment to confer...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_HUNTERSNEST_NAME">Hunter&#8217;s March Map</entry>
<entry name="G_PRINCE_DANCERS_REPEAT">My wish is granted... and now everything I love is lost...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_CURSED">Gara Takana! What has happened to you, Child Wielding Needle, to cause you such brutal weakening?&lt;hpage&gt;You are seeing the effects of a parasite, Shakra, a writhing entity implanted by force. It will not kill me, not quickly at least, but its presence wears greatly on my shell.&lt;page&gt;It is a horrid state you suffer. Fight yourself free, or find help with haste. I would not wish to see you defeated by such deceitful strength.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_ACCEPT_RETRY">Hoi! Let our mighty contest of shells commence again!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_TOOL_KIT">You&#8217;re in the habit of craftin&#8217; all kinds&#8217;a nasty tools&#8217;n traps, aint&#8217;cha? This kit&#8217;ll let you build &#8216;em even nastier, heh heh... </entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_BELLHART">Poshanka, Child Wielding Needle. This heart-home is cut free of its curse.&lt;page&gt;Tell me, was it your blade that brought its saving? My shock would be great if another here managed the feat.&lt;hpage&gt;I slew a tall creature above the town, a Weaver I suspect, though one twisted in purpose.&lt;hpage&gt;By voice and claw it aided, perhaps guided, the thread that strung the town. &lt;page&gt;Weaver? Those vicious old things! To our young we tell the tales, but had thought them long dead, only corpses bound in spires. &lt;hpage&gt;This one still lived, though if it was a Weaver, it was broken in a savage way.&lt;hpage&gt;Its own Silk was bound, pinned deep within its shell. A cruel punishment I&#8217;ve not before witnessed. &lt;page&gt;Even broken, my envy remains. A Weaver&#8217;s fabled skills... To meet one in combat means great challenge, and great pride in victory.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_GREYMOOR">&lt;hpage&gt;Fair greetings, Shakra. You are a welcome sight amidst the sodden gloom of these caverns. &lt;page&gt;Child Wielding Needle, your aspect is still sharp. My respect remains. Heed a warning, many fierce bugs roost nearby.&lt;page&gt;On the lake beyond this cave nest a ragged horde atop an old watermound. Their mastery of flight makes them dangerous. My shell will forever carry the score of their pins.&lt;page&gt;If you&#8217;re seeking a safer path, head back, towards this land&#8217;s core.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_ZAPNEST_REPEAT">Nuu is a long way from her safe lodging... perhaps she will stay in this nice, dark little squeezy place a little longer.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_DELIVERY">&lt;hpage&gt;Sherma, I bring supplies from the town of bells below. Since you are now caretaker here, I entrust them to you.&lt;page&gt;Oh, what a blessing! This will surely raise the hopes of our poor brothers and sisters.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_FINAL">Red maiden, you have some great task ahead of you, do you not? If so, then I fear the time of our final parting draws near.&lt;hpage&gt;You sense it true, Sherma. I shall soon descend to the darkness below the kingdom and quell the source of Pharloom&#8217;s rending.&lt;hpage&gt;If that task is achieved, my future may take me far from Pharloom, but know I have faith that you will hold these bugs together, and see them prosper.&lt;page&gt;Ah! In truth, I&#8217;m still only a fool, but I&#8217;ll hold dearly to your faith in me. That warmth will help me to endure whatever challenges lie ahead!&lt;page&gt;Now let me pray for you, dear friend, and may my hopes follow you into the deepest darkness and beyond!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_PIN_SHOP_NAME">Vendor Pins</entry>
<entry name="SHAKRA_GRAND_FORUM_REPEAT">The way forward is yours. Let us meet again soon.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MEET_GUARD_ACT3">&lt;hpage&gt;Shakra, you pit yourself against the black-threaded bugs? They are dangerous foes, even for a hardened warrior.&lt;page&gt;I relish such danger, and have little choice besides. These creatures besiege the town within. They are relentless, and empowered. &lt;hpage&gt;...It is the void, stretched up into this world and its husks. I know it well, this force, its nature. If it senses soul within, it will drive voracious towards it.&lt;page&gt;As you say! Many bugs now huddle within the bells. Nowhere else is safe with this black threat rising.&lt;page&gt;Some luck, at least, that I chose to remain, and can offer my rings&#8217; defence.&lt;hpage&gt;Shakra, I seek to end this new disaster, for in it I share much blame, but know, I shall need time to complete my task.&lt;hpage&gt;I ask you hold fast till then. This town and its bugs need a guardian, and I can think of none better.&lt;page&gt;Very well, Hornet Wielding Needle. A pact made strong. If you are working towards the venom&#8217;s end, I shall fight with faith renewed.</entry>
<entry name="SHAKRA_AID_READY">Let us charge on. My rings shall sing loud on the shells of our enemies. </entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_FINAL_2">And now, miss grown-up, the task is done! Nuu must be away.&lt;page&gt;But do not be sour! Just think! Pharloom is only one land. So many more must hide out there, filled full with beasts and scents and tastes, all waiting to be discovered.&lt;page&gt;For Nuu, her journey is only at its start. And for you, miss grown-up, Nuu wishes too your happy hunting, much and more!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MEET_BELLHART_ACT3">&lt;hpage&gt;Shakra, what has happened here? For these masses to huddle so amongst such destruction?&lt;page&gt;The dark-spun bugs, they besiege the town, relentless. I have defended against each wave anew, but they are empowered in foul ways, and I am much fatigued.&lt;hpage&gt;...It is the void, stretched up into this world and its husks. I know it well, that force, its nature. If it senses soul, it will drive voracious towards it.&lt;page&gt;As you say! All these bugs, gathered close within the bells... but nowhere else is safe with this black threat rising.&lt;hpage&gt;Shakra, I seek to end this new disaster, for in it I share much blame, but know, I shall need time to complete my task. I would ask you hold fast till then.&lt;hpage&gt;This town and its bugs needs a guardian, and I can think of none better.&lt;page&gt;Very well, Hornet Wielding Needle. A pact made strong. If you are working towards the venom&#8217;s end, I shall fight with faith renewed.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_BONEFOREST_FINAL">Eugh. Is it gettin&#8217; hotter down here? Mustier? Grindle&#8217;s been down here too long. Reckon it&#8217;s time to climb back up soon, to where all the serious treasures is!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_D_NAME">Dark Marker</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_HERO_WIN_PRE_1">So this is... defeat? Can it be? Huu... A shell so fast! Wonder of Pharloom! A bug whose pace could match my own.&lt;page&gt;Though I set a simple course, you have proven its match and more. Take this small reward, nimble bug, and remember well our grand contest!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BELLHART_WAKE">Oh, hoy there! Why, I must have dropped off to sleep as soon as I arrived!&lt;page&gt;Certainly, the pilgrim&#8217;s way is exhausting, but a good rest is a reward unto itself!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_HUNTERSNEST">That was a battle well-fought, Child Wielding Needle. Your master would be proud of you.&lt;hpage&gt;The one who trained me long ago... I never called her master. Whether she would be proud of what has become of me, I cannot say.&lt;page&gt;Nu-Hakkata! Whether she is dead or alive, have faith! Nothing a pupil does escapes their master&#8217;s sight!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_GREYMOOR_DESC">Wide, dim hollows, choked by rag and dust. The bugs who once tended these lands have clearly lost their way.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CITADEL_ENTRANCE_MEET">Red maiden! Dear sister! At last, our great pilgrimage is at its end!&lt;page&gt;Our faith never wavered, and now here awaits our glorious reward, the shining Citadel! Where all sing as one!&lt;hpage&gt;I will not tell you to turn back, for I know you will not, but I urge you at least to be cautious. Terrible things lurk within this Citadel, little pilgrim.&lt;page&gt;Oh, sister! There is no need for caution, and no need for fear. Let us step forward under guidance of our faith!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_BELLHART_TALK2">This vein of gilded bells creates an effectively defended settlement. I can see it once gave a long time of peace to its bugs.&lt;page&gt;And yet, look at their numbers now. Stricken by cursed thread. Only a few have survived.&lt;page&gt;We must learn from them, Child Wielding Needle. Peace is a slow poison that would wither even the hardiest bug.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_BELLHART_TALK1">&lt;hpage&gt;Your camp here looks comfortably set, Shakra. Are you planning to stay a time?&lt;page&gt;Perhaps, yes. This heart-home makes a fine base for now and later if needed.&lt;page&gt;Still! I must take care not to rest overlong. My shell would soften and my senses dull.&lt;page&gt;</entry>
<entry name="SETH_SHELLWOOD_MEET">Oh, hullo again! This time, I most certainly do recognise you! &#8216;Tis a pleasure to bump into you here, deep in this serene wood.&lt;page&gt;Do you have a name, like I do? Would you share it with me?&lt;hpage&gt;Certainly, sir. I am Hornet.&lt;hpage&gt;I notice you gazing at the buds above us... are they familiar to you, perhaps?&lt;page&gt;Hm? No, not at all. Very beautiful though! Perhaps I should gather some up before venturing on...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_A_DESC">You can use these to mark places of importance or reminders on your map.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These markers I have modelled after the sheen of my own shell. Perhaps you will think of me when you use them.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_CRAWL_REPEAT">There are signs that pilgrims once travelled even these crumbling paths, long ago. Now only the voracious worms nest here.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_REOFFER">Hoi! Nimble bug! Surely you have reconsidered? Let us discover our limits together! </entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_STOCKDEPLETED">You have purchased the last of my mapping stock, for now. Stay alive on your journey, and when our paths next cross we may trade again.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_RUMMAGE_REPEAT">Don&#8217;t be lingerin&#8217; here too long! We got snitchin&#8217; to do and we ain&#8217;t keen on company!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_DUSTPENS_REPEAT">If you venture further and higher into these caverns, beware. The sickly air only grows thicker.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BELLHART_REPEAT">I&#8217;ll be off soon, once I&#8217;m good and rested. Beyond the wood lies the final climb, and then at last we shall reach the Citadel!&lt;page&gt;Which of us will reach the Grand Gate first? If it&#8217;s me, I shall wait for you so we can enter together!</entry>
<entry name="SHAKRA_AID_REFUSE">If you would fight alone, I will say nothing more.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_ENCLAVE">&lt;hpage&gt;Fair meeting again, sir knight. I see this bell has drawn you too towards its safety.&lt;page&gt;Who would have guessed, sister! A safe corner, hidden so high atop Pharloom&#8217;s cursed crown!&lt;page&gt;Our fair village may have fallen, but for these fellows... these scared few, our honour charges us to keep them safe. Our hornlance shall raise for them! After some rest, of course.&lt;hpage&gt;Hold fast to your new charge, Garmond. See these bugs survive, and know I aim, in time near, to cut down this curse at its core.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_DUSTPENS_NAME">Sinner&#8217;s Road Map</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_BONEFOREST_S1">O-hoho! Into Grindle&#8217;s pockets they go! And for you, a secret to remember us by...&lt;page&gt;Beneath here and further on, the burly bellheads have a big, hot, gleaming hive! Full of all sorts of tasty snitchables!&lt;page&gt;But there&#8217;s this big gate they got down in its belly... shut tight, locked up. If you could wriggle through, you&#8217;d get your claws on all kindsa goodies!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_NOBENCH_ALT">You see this idol before us, red maiden? I have passed its like before, they mark our pilgrimage well.&lt;page&gt;If we sing to it, a miraculous shrine will rise from the ground, and we will have a place to rest! Such a wonder!&lt;hpage&gt;I suspect it is not song that rouses this shrine, but payment in rosaries.&lt;hpage&gt;I have encountered similar constructs on Pharloom&#8217;s paths. It seems this kingdom does not grant rest lightly.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_BONEFOREST_S3">O-hoho! Into Grindle&#8217;s pockets they go! And for you, a secret to remember us by...&lt;page&gt;There&#8217;s lots of pickings round here, right? Well, it&#8217;s all nothing compared to what they got hidden up, up above us. The great big Sitty-del they calls it!&lt;page&gt;A golden place, groaning with goodies! Could never steal it all in a thousand snitch-bug lifetimes they reckon!&lt;page&gt;Oh yes, that&#8217;s where ol&#8217; Grindle is headin&#8217;. Don&#8217;t you dare follow us, though! We want it all for us-selves!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_BONEFOREST_S2">O-hoho! Into Grindle&#8217;s pockets they go! And for you, a secret to remember us by...&lt;page&gt;You know where all them dreary raggedies are camping? Back near the ol&#8217; chapel? Well, beyond that chapel is a dirty great grave!&lt;page&gt;Not much in there but husks, right? But but! My sniffer tells me there&#8217;s something worth the trouble buried down at the bottom!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_MEET_END_VISITED">&lt;hpage&gt;The groaning docks, beyond the caverns of bone. There I have seen a vessel able to pass below, a heavy bell built for descent.&lt;hpage&gt;I need only gain access, and an operator to assist. I will investigate the docks, and uncover the means.&lt;page=M&gt;You&#8217;d be the first in an age to dive so deep, Old One. That space below remains long unseen, even to our family. &lt;hpage&gt;For those depths, I am more prepared than most. I will reach the base of this land, and know the truth of the new disaster we, together have wrought.</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_UNFINISHED_REPEAT">Why does it fade? Why can I not recall that sacred place?</entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_1">&lt;hpage&gt;Here you lie, monarch. Sunk so deep, yet still you cling to life. &lt;hpage&gt;Would you let your lands be choked black... to protect just her?</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_EXPLORING_ACT1_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;Take care, Garmond. Whatever dangers these lands present, I&#8217;m sure what waits in that Citadel will be worse.&lt;page&gt;Aye, sister! Until that Citadel is reached and justice is served, Zaza and I shall not fall.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_3">Letting you live was my rebellion, spider. I&#8217;ve denied my mother your silken strength. I&#8217;ve won.&lt;page&gt;She can thrash, and waste, and know her pathetic, broken child caused the mortal wound.&lt;page&gt;Rejoice! And let it all come down.&lt;hpage&gt;I will not. I have already stood the sentinel for one dying land. That role... I will never play again.&lt;hpage&gt;While I live, and possess the strength to resist, this kingdom, and the bugs within it, shall not fall.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_4">Hahahhaa! Spider. Spider. What a marvellous specimen you are! You fight and fight, heedless as the world crumbles around you.&lt;page&gt;Pharloom and her bugs will be crushed to dust, and still you&#8217;ll be vainly swinging your blade.&lt;hpage&gt;...There may still be a way to prevent that fate. I will claim the hidden power, the bloom that repels the dark.&lt;hpage&gt;Those snails share some fault in the snare, and their callous use of the void. They shall help me now to seek its counter.&lt;hpage&gt;I will return, child, when I bear the strength to dive below, and cut this land finally free of your mother&#8217;s grasp.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SHOP_REPEAT">After some tasty goodies? We never say no to a fair trade, heh heh! Take a look at what we&#8217;s got...</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_TOOL_POCKET">We could add a little pocket to yer tool pouch for you. You could pack even more goodies in there! All your shards&#8217;n sharp things!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_TUBE">&lt;hpage&gt;Shakra, if I may, I&#8217;d ask a small task of your carving talents.&lt;hpage&gt;Within the halls of the Citadel, I encountered a means of travel new to me, a network of pipes traversed in vessels propelled by steam and air.&lt;hpage&gt;That Citadel is a labyrinth, and pins to mark each station would prove useful to me.&lt;page&gt;What you describe sounds as hideous and unnatural as anything in that place. Still, if it will aid you, I shall craft the pins.&lt;page&gt;Seek me at a moment not long from now. The pins will be carved, and we may trade. </entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_MOSSGROTTO_DESC">These overgrown caves offer little challenge to a skilled warrior. A place for reflection, perhaps.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_NOBENCH_REPEAT">Fear not, red maiden! This shrine will surely rise for us, we only need to patiently wish for it!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_HEART_HINT_SHELLWOOD">&lt;page=M&gt;In the heights of the great wood, nestled deep in its roots, vines and branches, find the one who sowed the first seed.&lt;page=S&gt;They&#8217;re the very essence of the place, the nub of it all. Ain&#8217;t really a bug, to be told, but a powerful presence nonetheless.&lt;page=M&gt;We&#8217;d heard the Citadel once made grudging accord with that creature, sent their servants in reverence, even built a shrine up there somewhere. Maybe it&#8217;s worth you searching for it?</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_DUSTPENS_DESC">Old roads and passages overrun by roaches and their keepers. The ways are covered thick with filth. </entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_NOSTOCK">In this moment, I have no more items to trade. Perhaps, if we meet again on the roads ahead, I shall have crafted new goods to sell.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_PSALM_CYLINDER">You like this gleaming spinner I snitched from the big Sitty-dell? There&#8217;s a way to make it sing to you, or so they says!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_BONEFOREST_NAME">The Marrow Map</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_D_DESC">You can use these to mark places of importance or reminders on your map.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This dark-shell material is cold to the touch, and more resilient than it looks.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_BONEFOREST_DESC">Crumbling roads built upon the shells of ancient bugs. All of Pharloom rests upon these fragile foundations.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_CORALCAVERNS_DESC">Crusted heights above those howling steps. Signs suggest great warriors once ruled this winding place, though the sand has eroded much of their mark. </entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MENTOR_MEET">&lt;hpage&gt;To search these lands so thoroughly, Shakra... I wonder, who is it you hope to find?&lt;page&gt;Okklu-Din... a perceptive question. I travel in search of my mentor, the greatest of my tribe. I have followed her trail throughout this kingdom, but have so far failed to catch her.&lt;page&gt;She will have travelled much farther by now, but if I keep moving and stay vigilant, we shall reunite.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_SHADOW_REPEAT">The stone structures of this place suggest clear waters once ran throughout.&lt;page&gt;What fantasy that now seems! Even this swamp&#8217;s inhabitants seem spawned of its noxious nature. </entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BONEGATE_MEET_3">But look here! As soon as our sacred journey begins we are tested. This huge gate stands between us and the way forward.&lt;page&gt;Only holy prayer and song will open the way! In this kingdom, even mighty bone is moved by music!</entry>
<entry name="DICE_PILGRIM_DEPLETED">You win again! Never have I met a luckier pilgrim...&lt;hpage&gt;You mistake, sir. It was skill that won me this game. One must be careful not to rely merely on luck.&lt;page&gt;Hmph. Fairly said, sister.&lt;page&gt;I must confess something though. Truth is, I already lost the last of my rosaries. I can&#8217;t pay our last wager.&lt;page&gt;I do have something small for you, at least. These dice. They certainly seem to have taken a liking to you. Take them, in memory of our meeting.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_DIVE_2">&lt;page&gt;Who are you hoping you&#8217;ll find down there, spider? An ailing child and a Silk starved beast? &lt;page&gt;If so, I&#8217;m afraid we may sorely disappoint. What waits below is me no longer.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_BONEFOREST_INTRO">Hoy, you&#8217;re still hanging around then? Quiet in here. Good for hidin&#8217; out.&lt;page&gt;You gots the li&#8217;l clicky-clackies on you then, eh? The rolly-roundies? What the shops like to swap for?</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_A_NAME">Shell Marker</entry>
<entry name="G_PRINCE_DANCERS_MEET">You... So, it is done... My wish granted before ever I arrived...&lt;hpage&gt;The bronze pair that danced this chamber, it is clear, tall bug, how closely they mimicked your shell. Was it you who provided their inspiration?&lt;page&gt;Not I, warrior. For this place, my heart holds only loathing...&lt;page&gt;The dancers... they were the last free act of my partner... Always hopeful. Always naive.&lt;page&gt;His whole he gave, in desperate trade to see our own caves left safe. His shell and soul became the mould.&lt;page&gt;So long, I dared not visit... Even as our lands fell to thread and ruin... Instead I wasted, a coward caged, too weak to witness his grace bound in parody so cruel.&lt;hpage&gt;Take some solace, tall bug. His soul is now free from that shell of iron, and the fate that befell your lands, this Citadel too has been claimed full by it.&lt;page&gt;Aye... Slim consolation, warrior, now that everything I loved is lost...</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_CLOVER_HEART">&lt;page=M&gt;What&#8217;s this? That&#8217;s an unexpected heart you&#8217;re holding, Old One...&lt;page=M&gt;We can guess to its source, though we&#8217;d believed it long gone from these lands. &lt;hpage&gt;The heart of a graceful lord. In its taking I was able to witness his caves and kingdom as once they flourished.&lt;hpage&gt;A stunning sight. Unique. All gone... Lost to the pale monarch... and the system to keep her caged.</entry>
<entry name="DICE_PILGRIM_NOTENOUGH">A beat of rosaries is our wager. Once you find enough, I&#8217;d be happy to play.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_EXTRA_MEET">Nimble bug, you return refreshed! And so perfectly timed, for I have a new challenge prepared.&lt;page&gt;The course shall remain the same as last, but length, the laps, will greatly extend.&lt;hpage&gt;You propose a test of endurance? I have undertaken many in my time.&lt;page&gt;Excellent! Excellent! Though know, for this race, I can only provide slight reward for victory.&lt;page&gt;What say you, nimble bug? Let us stride fast forth!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_SPAR_DECLINE">&lt;hpage&gt;Another time, Shakra. I am always eager to learn, but for now my tasks call me away. &lt;page&gt;Bakelo! Answer to your tasks, then. My rings shall await your return.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_MEET_ACT1">Gurrroo! Fellow warrior, if you are wishing to lock blades, know you stand before the honoured knight Garmond, and brave companion Zaza. Together we will face bold to any challenge!&lt;hpage&gt;I have no wish to fight you, sir bug. It is heartening to meet another on these roads of sound mind, and with fortitude enough to fight back against the haunted husks.&lt;page&gt;Aye! Too many, these unnatural opponents! We did hope Pharloom&#8217;s vast expanse would still possess some place free of that tainted thread. &lt;page&gt;Alas, so far we&#8217;ve encountered only violence and decay. We greatly fear the Haunting afflicts this kingdom all.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MEET_BRIEF">Poshanka! Edges sharp and senses keen!&lt;page&gt;In my land, that is the way warriors greet each other. For though you are a child barely hatched, you are also a warrior. Your stance, your weapon, your movements all proclaim it so.&lt;page&gt;I am a navigator amongst my tribe, and have been making maps of these lands. I can trade them with you, and supplies, if you wish.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_BELLHART_REPEAT">I have mapping supplies still, if you would care to trade.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_GREYMOOR_NAME">Greymoor Map</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;Child, if your wish is to gain learning of this land&#8217;s creatures, why not hunt them yourself?&lt;page&gt;Ma? Nuu, herself to hunt? No, no! Is not Nuu&#8217;s nature to hunt, is hers to come later and learn. Such is the way of things!&lt;page&gt;But you... a predator! Know it from your smells can clever Nuu! So Nuu asks you to cut and record, so we both may learn!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CITADEL_SPA_ENCLAVE">&lt;hpage&gt;Little pilgrim, these baths provide some respite from the dangers without, but there is a still safer place high on the other side of the Citadel.&lt;hpage&gt;A settlement has formed around the old shrine there. The bell housed within seems to provide some sanctuary from the dangers of the Haunting.&lt;hpage&gt;Your brother and sister pilgrims who now huddle around it would be glad of your company, I am sure.&lt;page&gt;Oh, how wonderful! Yes, I will make my way over there with haste... after I have bathed a little longer. I want to arrive fresh and clean to such a holy place!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_QUILL">You hold many charts, Child Wielding Needle. You should consider trading for a quill.&lt;page&gt;With a quill in claw, your maps can be further extended from your own travels. Record enough and you may, in time, come to know this kingdom all.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_BELLHART_ALT">Poshanka! Child Wielding Needle. You too have discovered this haven of bells.&lt;page&gt;For a long time, I avoided this place for sense of something strange. Now arrived, I find it free, and its few remaining residents offering trade and welcome.&lt;hpage&gt;I slew a tall creature above the town, a Weaver I suspect, though one twisted in purpose.&lt;hpage&gt;It was her you may have sensed. A formidable force, even aged. By voice and claw she aided, perhaps guided, the haunted thread that grasps these lands. &lt;page&gt;Weaver? Those vicious things. To our young we tell the tales, but had thought them long dead, only corpses bound in spires. &lt;hpage&gt;This one still lived, though if it was a Weaver, it was broken in a savage way.&lt;hpage&gt;Its own Silk was bound, pinned deep within its shell. A cruel punishment I&#8217;ve not before witnessed. &lt;page&gt;Even broken, my envy remains. A Weaver&#8217;s fabled skills... To meet one in combat means great challenge, and great pride in victory.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_BONEBOTTOM">This outpost that the shambling pilgrim-bugs have built for themselves... Dondakku!&lt;page&gt;Where are the armaments? The watch-poles? Never have I seen such a poorly defended encampment!&lt;hpage&gt;The pilgrims here seem to have no mind for war, Shakra. I suspect most depart for the Citadel soon after their arrival.&lt;page&gt;Hmph. If they persist in their carelessness, they will find only death in these harsh lands.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_CITADEL_MEET">What&#8217;s this? The little spider climbs so high, here to stand aquiver at our startling Citadel.&lt;hpage&gt;Pale child, you return only to mock? Neither you nor your land have proven my match. This sleeping Citadel shall be no different.&lt;page&gt;Spider, dear. Why must you remain so distressingly... optimistic? The power that waits above, you cannot conceive, her who would snuff that hope with barely a glance.&lt;hpage&gt;Fool child. You still think me blind to the form of your liege? Having coming this far?&lt;hpage&gt;This land&#8217;s grandeur, the devotion of its bugs, and the curse that befalls them. The signs are clear.&lt;hpage&gt;Your kingdom is in the thrall of a creature beyond bug, one of that higher caste.&lt;hpage&gt;Whatever its desire for my Silk and my shell, it shall find I&#8217;m quite attached to both.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_JUDGE">Aren&#8217;t those solemn judge-bugs nice? They do not speak or sing, but I sense great wisdom behind their gleaming gazes!&lt;hpage&gt;Beware them, little one. Wise or not, their judgements are often followed by violence. Many of your fellow pilgrims have fallen to them on these great steps.&lt;page&gt;Oh...? But even the fallen will sometimes stand again, and all pilgrimages will be completed, yes? That&#8217;s how I&#8217;ve heard it!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_HUNTERSNEST_REPEAT">These twisting tunnels hide many worthy opponents, but many traps as well. Watch your footing closely.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_TUBE_PIN_DESC">As you requested, these pins will mark the travel stations within that hideous structure of steel and steam. </entry>
<entry name="COURIER_TALL_THANK_PT2">&lt;hpage&gt;Head fast for Bellhart, Pill. These lands are not for travelling without a sharp blade in claw.&lt;page&gt;Aye! Yes! To Bellhart, and my brother, I shall fly quickly-quick. If you pass that way again, stop and give greeting!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MENTOR">&lt;hpage&gt;Who are you calling for, Shakra? Your voice echoes through the caverns.&lt;page&gt;I came deeper into Pharloom in search of my mentor, the greatest of my tribe. I could not keep pace though, and her trail grew cold.&lt;page&gt;She will have travelled much farther by now, but if I keep moving and stay vigilant I will reunite with her.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_SPAR_REOFFER">We must never let our shells soften, or Pharloom&#8217;s sharp teeth will sink in quick.&lt;page&gt;Would you duel with me, Hornet Wielding Needle? Together we shall sharpen one another&#8217;s skill.</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_CARMELITA_CORPSE_REPEAT">I&#8217;ll wish you success in your grand task, miss, but forgive me my sadness for knowing the cruel cost...</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_TRAPPED2">Hurry it up, let us out quickly then! We got places to go, bugs to see, trinkets to pilfer!</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_CLOVER_MEET_1">Warrior... I heard your approach. Why do you come? Surely you&#8217;ve no desire to see these long collapsed caves?&lt;hpage&gt;The way was open, sir. I merely followed the path through. Am I correct to guess you were once a resident of these borderlands?&lt;page&gt;Aye... and glorious they were, in their time. Pharloom&#8217;s end approaches, but my caves, these caves, fell to fate long before. &lt;page&gt;Of that fair land, I am the last... Now to remain till the end, and remember the splendour that was...</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_ZAPNEST_SLAP1">Miss grown-up, you have hunted long with little rest, thinks Nuu.&lt;page&gt;Perhaps you are covered in too many juices, weighed down by beastly filth? Let sweet Nuu clean you, make you fresh!</entry>
<entry name="LACE_MEET_4">Delicious! I like you already!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_DEEP_MEMORY2">&lt;page=M&gt;We could do it. The spell can be cast, with enough power, enormous power, equal maybe to that monarch...&lt;hpage&gt;I cannot grant you mine, if it even were enough. My strength is still needed to face her below. Where else do you propose we seek a source?&lt;page=M&gt;From Pharloom! Ho ho ho! Remember, ours is a kingdom of wishes granted.&lt;page=B&gt;Pharloom was not born of that monarch, Old One. Power existed in these lands even before she bound them beneath her.&lt;page=B&gt;Grnk. Seek the old hearts of our kingdom and the last successors to bear their strength.&lt;page=M&gt;They&#8217;re still out there, hidden away, much faded by the pale one&#8217;s long dominion. You must make them stir.&lt;page=M&gt;We will teach you how, in the way befitting a Weaver, a sombre song to reach down into their memories and enliven them a final time. </entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_CITADEL_SLAP_2">Owoww, what a rotten turn! Keep your nasty junk to yourself, then!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_BONEFOREST_OFFER">O-hoho! Share some of your little clicky-clackies with us, help us fill our pockets. If you do, we&#8217;ll share a sneaky secret with you!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_HINT_WISP">Miss grown-up, for your continued huntings you should climb up, up above here, above the tallest spinning towers!&lt;page&gt;Hidden in the dark thickets are strange bugs who call up dancing flames. So pretty! So warm!&lt;page&gt;But when Nuu tried to crawl near, the flames became angry and swooped all around! Poor Nuu was half roasted!&lt;page&gt;Nuu leaves it to you, miss grown-up, to climb up there and cut those flames apart. For our journal, such must be done.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_JUDGESTEPS">Poshanka! Child Wielding Needle, have you seen trace of my master nearby? I feel she was here only recently!&lt;hpage&gt;I cannot say for certain, Shakra, though if she travels seeking skilled opponents, these steps would serve her well. The warriors watching over them are formidable.&lt;page&gt;True! Impressive guardians they are, fighting defensively and loath to leave their stations. They swing their weapons with a cold brutality that should not be underestimated.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MASTER_MEET">Poshanka, Hornet Wielding Needle. For that is your name, is it not? I have heard it spoken in this land with reverence.&lt;page&gt;I had hoped you would accept my summons. In these moments one is good, but two is best.&lt;hpage&gt;I would not deny the wish, Shakra. A sombre ceremony seemed likely at this trail&#8217;s end, and I am sadly proved correct. This then is your master?&lt;page&gt;The fiercest of my tribe, here she lies. I called her master, true, but she was mother just as much, more by far than the bug who bore me.&lt;hpage&gt;Among the many marvels of this kingdom, she found a fine place to meet her end.&lt;page&gt;Ended by age... My tribe would call that shame, but I see only strength unbeaten.&lt;page&gt;Even as her shell betrayed her, she walked this kingdom&#8217;s breadth. It was her trail followed that allowed me to share witness to its dignity.&lt;page&gt;Hornet Wielding Needle, you too have journeyed these many paths, as my master before us. Join me now for her song-sending.&lt;page&gt;It is time for her soul to walk beyond her shell...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_BONEBOTTOM_REPEAT">From this safe vantage, I can keep watch for threats while I work. These lowlands are brittle and dangerous. Keep your weapon close.</entry>
<entry name="SETH_FESTIVAL_REPEAT">Have you tried your claw at the games? Rollicking good fun, don&#8217;t you think?&lt;page&gt;I wonder if I could score a little higher if I tried again...</entry>
<entry name="LACE_TOWER_DEFEAT_2">After all... it&#8217;s you that she wants... is it not?</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_ACCEPT">Hoi! Magnificent! May our mighty contest of shells commence.&lt;page&gt;But a final note, nimble bug! If ever you run off course or desire a quick convene, simply play what music you&#8217;re able and my companion shall whisk you back to our starting line.&lt;page&gt;Now! The track calls us. Allow me a moment to assemble a course worthy to test our skill.&lt;page&gt;</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_RESCUE_MEET2">&lt;hpage&gt;Hold your gratitude, little one. The dead are stirring.</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_HORNET_MEMORY1">&lt;hpage&gt;It is time, shamans. I have the hearts, enough as requested. Enough to build your spell, yes?&lt;page=B&gt;Aye. We&#8217;re ready. Still, it&#8217;s a sad set you&#8217;re holding there, strength such as few shall ever know... and all about to burn for Pharloom&#8217;s saving.&lt;page=S&gt;I&#8217;ll warn ya, Old One, this first part might not be pleasant, but we&#8217;ll get you in there, deep as needed.&lt;page=M&gt;Now you&#8217;ve only to ready yourself for what comes after. Lay up on the dais and we&#8217;ll begin.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_PEAK_REPEAT">Charting the heights of this great mount would prove a mighty challenge. For now, I have seen only its base.&lt;page&gt;Once I have completed the search for my master, I would like to return and attempt the climb in full.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_CRAWL_DESC">Worm-ridden caverns, shaking and unstable. There remain faint signs that pilgrims once travelled these tight paths.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_DEFEATED">Hooof... let us stop the duel there.&lt;page&gt;I... hoof... I hope in my excitement I did not... hoof... bring down my lance too heavy upon you, sister.&lt;hpage&gt;It was combat honourably conducted, sirs. But now, we should all of us keep moving. It will not remain quiet here for long.&lt;page&gt;Y-yes, of course. Our good works are never done, and we must press ever on. There is no time to waste!</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_RETRY">Don&#8217;t let defeat weigh on you, nimble bug! Simply step to the challenge. Let us soar swift together again!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_TALK1_CITADEL">&lt;hpage&gt;What cause saw you first ascend to this Citadel, Garmond?&lt;page&gt;Mine is only the most sacred quest, sister! One shared with my most trusted companion, dear Zaza.&lt;page&gt;We sought this Citadel, to stand before its rulers, and demand their answer! By force if necessary! All for our dear village to whom we pledge our shells. &lt;page&gt;The fearsome haunting of thread, it overcame our fair folk.... We are all that remain, left to carry their memory, and the hope to see some justice paid.</entry>
<entry name="DICE_PILGRIM_MEET">Ahh, a fellow pilgrim. I&#8217;ve been praying alone here too long, with only the wind&#8217;s voice to join mine.&lt;page&gt;We&#8217;re so close. Our pilgrimage is almost over. Just one final, brutal climb, hm?&lt;hpage&gt;The Citadel is near, pilgrim. You must have had some strength in you. Few of your fellows seem to reach these heights.&lt;page&gt;Aye, the roads become lonelier the longer they&#8217;re travelled and the higher we climb.&lt;page&gt;It takes a lot of luck and a lot of faith to make it this far, though I&#8217;m sure I don&#8217;t need to tell you that.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_HERO_WIN_POST_LAST">Huu... You have done it... Huu. Huu... Hoof.&lt;page&gt;Never would I have believed, a shell so fast in all of Pharloom! Wonder of wonders!&lt;page&gt;You have proven it, nimble bug, fulfilled my wish, seen my pace matched and beaten, my limits broken wide.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_OFFER">Gurro! I have a notion for you, sister. What say we cross our weapons here before we move on? Engage in some rollicking combat together? Have no fear, I will not strike a mortal blow!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_FINAL">&lt;hpage&gt;Sir knight, I am sorry... This was the only means to free you from the cursed threads.&lt;page&gt;Hohhhh... fret not.... little one...&lt;page&gt;Be proud... you&#8217;ve grown so strong!&lt;page&gt;Zaza... let us just rest a little... and then we&#8217;ll be away...</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_COMPLETE_4">Nuu&#8217;s wish, it is granted. But miss grown-up will continue cutting creatures and adding them to our journal, of course?&lt;hpage&gt;I will. Knowing a creature&#8217;s form and habits is an advantage that can decide the outcome of a battle. Recording these details is worth the effort.&lt;page&gt;Oh yes! Is very much worth it! Nuu hopes you will share your new learnings with her often!&lt;page&gt;And take a gift to help with your huntings, miss grown-up! Nuu will add a pocket to your tool pouch, for the bringing of many tools on your hunts!&lt;page&gt;</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_MASK_SHARD">Just a piece of a mask, innit? Don&#8217;t ask us where the other bits are... you&#8217;ll have to sniff &#8216;em out for yourself!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_PEAK_NAME">Mount Fay Map</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_COMPLETE_1">&lt;hpage&gt;Nuu, I have completed your request, recording many creatures of Pharloom in the journal.&lt;page&gt;Oooh, ooh! Ma ma ma! Look here at the marvelous beasts and bugs, all listed so beautifully!&lt;page&gt;Miss grown-up, so many creatures now you have cut and beat and smashed! Their essences linger on you, their scents mixing with your own!&lt;page&gt;Oooh, ma... Nuu simply must sample it for herself!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_GRAND_FORUM_REPEAT">You go on ahead. Zaza and I will keep guard here and catch any stragglers.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_COMPLETE_3">Nuu understands, ma. To sup on such a fierce predator&#8217;s juices would be divine... but is not right to do. Such behaviour is unfriendly.&lt;page&gt;Nuu&#8217;s wish to see many fine beasts, though... miss grown-up, you have surely granted it! All of Nuu&#8217;s thanks goes to you!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_BONE">I will soon leave these crumbling roads, but if you stop by the settlement below we may meet again. I pass there often to trade with the pilgrims.</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_STAG_MEET">Here, the trail of the stag touched pale... We hunted her, felled her, as none before were able...&lt;page&gt;Proof it became, of our majesty... mark of our divine right...</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_SPOOL_PIECE">Beautiful this, a glowy little piece of somethin&#8217;. Stinks of them horrid crawling whisperers a bit, so might be dangerous. You should take it! Give us your rosaries and lighten my claws of it!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_ENEMYFIGHT">Ho, sister! A grand victory achieved, again. The haunted might of this place cannot stand against our pure hearts!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_DEEP_MEMORY4">&lt;page=M&gt;This task before you... This is mortal power you would claim, the hearts of bugs. It will cost their last strength to save this land.&lt;page=M&gt;Even we have some hesitation in this. Despite our desire to touch their power, we&#8217;d never wished to see it expended so utterly.&lt;hpage&gt;Better to leave your land weak in wonder, if it means your shells, and those of your fellows, stay intact. </entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_ACCEPT">Gurrrooooo! Gallantly answered, sister! Prepare your weapon!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_FINAL_1">Uaahhhhh! Miss grown-up... your journal is bursting with every sort of creature! Overflowing! Surely, we can call this complete!&lt;page&gt;To think, that such a task could even be done! So clever is Nuu, to have set such a fierce predator onto the work!&lt;hpage&gt;These vast lands hold so much life, and to catalogue it all has taught me greatly. It is an effort worth continuing even after I leave this kingdom.&lt;page&gt;Ooh ma, such a hunger is worthy indeed! You and I are of accord, miss grown-up, hunters both. Our methods are different but our appetites have become very similar!&lt;page&gt;Nuu has for you this token, a symbol of all your efforts, and a marker of your true nature. It carries with it her sweet, sweet smell!</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_ENTRY_REPEAT">All bowed before we princes green...</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_TALK1">&lt;hpage&gt;What cause sees you travelling these blighted lands, Garmond? Do you also seek the Citadel above?&lt;page&gt;Aye! But do not mistake a valorous adventurer for a mere pilgrim. Mine is a sacred quest, shared with my most trusted companion, dear Zaza.&lt;page&gt;We seek that Citadel not for its gifts. Nay, sister! We seek its rulers, to demand their answer! By force if necessary! For our dear village to whom we pledge our shells. &lt;page&gt;The fearsome haunting of thread, it overcame our fair folk... We are all that remain, left to carry their memory, and the hope to see some justice paid.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_CRAWL">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, Shakra. It was a welcome surprise to hear your call echo through these crumbling tunnels. How goes the search for your master?&lt;page&gt;Poshanka! It is a difficult task to track anything in these caverns while the worms ceaselessly churn the rock.&lt;page&gt;Still, I can see that my master has travelled here. Her path within this land winds strangely... I wonder at her intent.&lt;page&gt;It is no matter though. She can enlighten me when again we meet. Until then, I will continue in her shadow.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SAVED2">Lockin&#8217; us up in a place like this... what a shameful act!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BELLBEAST_REPEAT">Come now beast, let us hear your voice! Sing with me, sing with me, sing sing sing! Make caverns echo and great roads ring!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_REFUSE_2">Very well, sister. Perhaps it is better that we all just rest here a little longer.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_EXITED_BY_BUG">Nimble bug! You forfeited the race? It is true that sometimes a reset it needed, for the health of mind and shell.&lt;page&gt;But what say you now? Surely you are eager to return to the track. Let us soar swift together again!</entry>
<entry name="SETH_CITADEL_REPEAT">These black threads... they reach upwards with such a powerful longing. No wonder they can force themselves through even mighty stone!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_SIMPLE_KEY">Us snitchbugs can wriggle into any place we want, but with this key even a big oafy bug like you can get through a locked door!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_HEART_HINT_ANT">&lt;page=M&gt;Through their march, at the far border of these lowlands, seek the last queen of the ant hunters. We can sense her still... just.&lt;page=B&gt;In youth, her voice united the wild tribes. Gave them the strength to resist the pale monarch&#8217;s will... longer than most at least.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CITADEL_ENTRANCE_REPEAT">Let us head on, sister! Together we shall step forward under guidance of our faith!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_SHELLWOOD_RAPTURED">Needle Child. Hakk! I encountered a settlement near here, at the core of a vein of old bells. The bugs there were snared silent on a web of Silk.&lt;page&gt;It seemed the pernicious trap of some unseen predator. I left quickly, making sure to avoid the glimmering threads.&lt;hpage&gt;I passed the town myself. The thread sickness, I&#8217;ve seen its like upon the roads, but there it does not discriminate.&lt;hpage&gt;The curse that strikes the town, it is driven, focused. A cold use of Silk at a concerning scale.&lt;hpage&gt;If the path permits, I will investigate its source.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_REOFFER_FINAL">What say you, nimble bug? Though no reward remains to give, I would delight to soar together with you again!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_GRAND_FORUM_ASLEEP">Snnnrk... Zaza... Snnnrnrrk... Look sharp my lad...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ROSARIES">You haven&#8217;t enough rosaries for trading? The mad pilgrims in the overgrown village near here always carry some with them.&lt;page&gt;Will you take what you need from them? Leaving them to wander their path endlessly is a false mercy. </entry>
<entry name="GILLY_HUNTERTRAP_CAUGHT">Ho, what clever traps the red-shells lay out in defence of their lands!&lt;page&gt;Impressive that you managed to survive such a brutal blow. Your shell must be mighty thick!&lt;hpage&gt;Thick enough, though I&#8217;d rather have avoided the trap altogether.&lt;hpage&gt;I&#8217;ll let it be a reminder to remain wary, even when no foes are nearby.</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_END">...Oh. Excuse me.</entry>
<entry name="DICE_PILGRIM_REMEET">Well, what a pleasure. The road has carried you back to me.&lt;page&gt;Care for a few games of dice, while we&#8217;re here? For the same wager, a beat of rosaries? Just sit here beside me and we&#8217;ll begin.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_DOCKS_DESC">These docks, I thought them small when first I passed. Now I feel the structure&#8217;s true bulk hides below the molten lake.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_PIN_BELLWAY_DESC">The bellways, gilded veins that run throughout the lands. Supposedly, they were once used for travel?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These pins will mark stations on your map.</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_BOSS_1">Again... to see... this land abandoned... betrayed...&lt;page&gt;...And a throne I could not sit alone...&lt;hpage&gt;You were mortal bugs, caught beneath a being pale... Devotion or destruction... these are the only fates my kind allow.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_REPEAT_ACT3">The world has grown much dangerous, but still we must learn! Cut through the black threads, miss grown-up, and hunt down every beast of Pharloom!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_SHADOW">&lt;hpage&gt;Shakra, you too brave these bogs? The heights of Pharloom offer harsh welcome.&lt;page&gt;So winds my master&#8217;s path, and so I follow. Yet true you speak! This is no place for me.&lt;page&gt;That Citadel&#8217;s shadow falls heavy here. I can sense its horrid bulk besides.&lt;page&gt;It is no surprise to see it choke these caverns dank and stagnant. That monstrosity of metal and stone cares not for the lands it consumes.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_QUILL_NAME">Quill</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_WILDS_REPEAT">My master would have found her way to these wilds, I am sure. Her warrior&#8217;s sense has no equal. Surely, I must be drawing closer to her!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_ENEMYFIGHT_REPEAT">Leave us to our noble hunt, sister! The Citadel&#8217;s twisted bugs still infest these gilded halls. Many are their numbers, but we shall see their life&#8217;s thread severed.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_C_DESC">You can use these to mark places of importance or reminders on your map.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The shell of the red-hunters makes for a vivid marker indeed.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_DUSTPENS">How dank and fetid are these ancient roads, sister! My delicate whiskers are nearly overcome by the stench of evil in the air.&lt;page&gt;Woe betide those with delicate senses, such as poor Zaza here. The shadow of that ghastly Citadel falls heavily upon this place!&lt;hpage&gt;I&#8217;ve seen many mighty structures fall to decay in my time. Such places often become home to predators. Keep your sights trained on what lurks in the fog, sirs.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_CITADEL_SLAP_1">Hoy, you been creepin&#8217; around this dusty old place for while then, eh? You must be carryin&#8217; a lot of goodies with you! Let a poor old snitchfly &#8216;ave a quick look!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_MEET_OPENED2">I&#8217;m Sherma, by the way. Just another humble pilgrim like yourself. If you ever need assistance on the road ahead, sing out my name and I&#8217;ll be sure to find you. Me and my lucky chime are at your service!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_CITADEL_MEET_REPEAT">We ain&#8217;t leavin&#8217; &#8216;til we&#8217;re done pilfering! You be off, if you&#8217;re so scared!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_DELIVERY_POST">Please take some rosaries in exchange, red maiden!&lt;page&gt;Though in these dark times their promise of holy reward may never be met, still they carry with them our fondest well-wishes.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BONEGATE_OPENED_2">Gate, gate, gate! Nicest gate I&#8217;ve met!&lt;br&gt;Gate, gate, gate! Greatest miracle yet! Ha ha ha!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_MEET_END_NOTVISITED">&lt;page=M&gt;Those docks, atop the lake of flame, they still possess the means to pass below, though you&#8217;d be the first in an age to dare the descent.&lt;hpage&gt;Then my path is clear. Remain in your sanctuary and await my return. If this land can be saved, you may have a part to play yet.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_YESNO">Race Sprintmaster Swift?</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_HUNTERTRAP">Ho, what clever traps the red-shells lay in defence of their lands!&lt;page&gt;I&#8217;ve narrowly avoided a few nasty ends myself. It certainly adds a thrill to my investigations...</entry>
<entry name="SETH_FESTIVAL_MEMENTO">Well now! How brilliant! In all these fine games you have matched my scores and more!&lt;page&gt;What wonder to be here, and able to witness a display of such profound talent.&lt;hpage&gt;Besting your scores proved an immense challenge, Seth, and yet you seem to have achieved them yourself with relative ease.&lt;page&gt;You flatter me! But yes, my own aptitude continues to surprise me. So many skills I cannot recall learning... &lt;page&gt;But do not underplay your own achievements, for they too are significant, inspiring even!&lt;page&gt;In fact, for my deep respect I insist you take this small medallion. I found it within my belongings, and know not where I came upon it, but it has a most pleasant sense.&lt;page&gt;Let it serve as marker of a friendship I feel has only just begun.&lt;hpage&gt;Thank you, Seth. I shall keep it close.</entry>
<entry name="DICE_PILGRIM_MEET2">While we rest for the journey ahead, care to test your luck with a game of dice? You know how to play, I trust?&lt;hpage&gt;I&#8217;m sure I can grasp the rules quickly enough, sir. What is the wager?&lt;page&gt;A beat of rosaries on each roll. What say you? Sound fair? Let our worries roll away with the dice!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_ENCLAVE_MEET1_ALT">Hrm...? Oh, hoy there! &#8216;Tis a pleasure to meet you here at the end of our long journey, sister.&lt;page&gt;I am Sherma, a simple pilgrim like yourself. What a wonder to find ourselves finally here, eh?&lt;page&gt;Rising at last to the heights of the Citadel and being amongst so many of our brothers and sisters... it is a blessing indeed. Yes, a blessing.&lt;hpage&gt;Your voice belies some hesitation in that belief, little pilgrim. To have travelled this far is to have seen the reality of this broken place. What do you make of it, truly?</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_RUMMAGE_SONG8">Hoy! You again? This place used to be nice and quiet, but now we can&#8217;t get a moment&#8217;s peace!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_DEFEATEDHORNET">Ahh, sister! You have awoken. I hope that our powerful strikes did not leave you in too weak a condition.&lt;page&gt;We would even be willing to duel again, if you still have the strength!</entry>
<entry name="SETH_GREYMOOR_MEET">&lt;hpage&gt;Sir Guardian... I scarcely thought we would meet again after our encounter.&lt;page&gt;Hm? Apologies friend, I fear I don&#8217;t recognise you. And I&#8217;m sure I would remember such a striking figure!&lt;hpage&gt;...Pay no heed, sir. It seems I mistook you for another.&lt;hpage&gt;You are... a traveller through these quaking lands, I take it?&lt;page&gt;I suppose I am indeed! I was born into this world not long ago, waking beside a lake with only this weapon laying beside me.&lt;page&gt;Seth is my name, though I know not who gave it to me.&lt;page&gt;The custom of the newly-born is to explore the world, is it not? So that is what I have set out to do! I will rest here a moment, then continue my journey.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_MEET_ACT3">Miss grown-up! What sweet surprise for Nuu! The world rumbles and the black threads stretch. Not safe now to wander.&lt;page&gt;But you! You are adult yes? Fully grown? Ready to hunt, no matter the darkness?&lt;hpage&gt;Certainly I am no child, young one.&lt;page&gt;Perfect then! Nuu must ask a wish! For her, you would seek Pharloom&#8217;s many fabulous bugs and cut them.&lt;page&gt;Cut them with your blade! Cut them with your mature spirit! Cut them with your savage adult heart!&lt;page&gt;Would you help Nuu? Before it all ends? Could you take her scroll, and fill its pages with the learnings of your cuts?</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC2">...Great strides move the world, but small steps shouldn&#8217;t be overlooked...&lt;page&gt;...One mystery leads to another. Scrutinising the belly of the thing will prove useful...&lt;hpage&gt;The meaning behind your musings is as opaque as ever. Would you converse with me directly, sir?&lt;page&gt;...Trust yourself. And each other. The solution is always within grasp...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_SHELLWOOD_REPEAT">The creatures of this wood can disguise themselves amongst the many branches. Watch for unexpected movement and be prepared to strike.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_2">Spider dear, what a delight to have you visit! It is oh so lonely here at the bottom of the world.&lt;hpage&gt;I cannot share your mirth, child. Your small rebellion above now causes this kingdom&#8217;s collapse.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_HUNTERSNEST_DEEP">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, Shakra. I had a sense I would find you in these winding tunnels, filled as they are with the marks of combat.&lt;page&gt;Poshanka! You trust your instincts rightly. The red-shelled warriors who carved out these roads make for excellent opponents indeed.&lt;page&gt;I would gladly spend much time here, testing myself against their blades and cunning traps, but I must keep to my task. As should you!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_BLACK_THREAD_EXHAUSTED">Hahhh... hahhh... oh, sister. What a toll it exacts on us... this endless combat! Certainly when peace finally comes, we will be in the right mind to appreciate it...&lt;hpage&gt;You place too much burden upon yourself, sir.&lt;hpage&gt;Though I share your ambition to free this land from its curse, I counsel you to rest, even if only for a short while.&lt;page&gt;Us, rest? While you, my dear sister, fight on so gallantly? Hahhhh... we cannot.&lt;page&gt;What would our old village think of us, were we to quit our charge? No, regardless of what you may believe, there&#8217;s strength enough still in these old shells!</entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_DIVE_1">&lt;hpage&gt;Child, I hold the means to descend. Let us meet one final time, and quell this black ruin of our making.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_GIVEN">&lt;hpage&gt;Learning about a land&#8217;s inhabitants is a worthwhile undertaking. Perhaps you are more grown than you realise, Nuu.&lt;page&gt;Ma! Such delicious praise will make Nuu shrivel! Go now! Hunt, and prey, and begin our learning!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_DOCKS">Child Wielding Needle. What do you make of this huge, groaning structure?&lt;hpage&gt;The scale of it all impresses me. If this is merely an outpost of the Citadel above, then their capital must be grand beyond measure.&lt;page&gt;Yokkala... Perhaps so. They must have prized indeed the work done here, to build something so vast in such a dangerous place.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_C_NAME">Hunt Marker</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GUARD_REPEAT_ACT3">Seek swift to calm our crying land, Hornet Wielding Needle. And know that I shall remain here, to stand against these husks gone dark.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_RESCUE_END_REPEAT">I&#8217;ll bring the healing supplies to the settlement with all haste, red maiden.&lt;page&gt;Fear not on my behalf. My fellow pilgrims are all praying for me, and thereby no harm will befall me!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_REPEAT">&#8216;Tis now my charge to care for those who stay here, including yourself. If I can aid you in any way, please let me know!</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_REMEET">Oh, what a shock! Discovered again so easily! Like a hapless little hatchling!&lt;page&gt;If you&#8217;re going to make a sport of tracking me, I&#8217;ll have to redouble my efforts at camouflage!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_PEAK_DESC">The jagged crest looming over all of Pharloom. Its whipping winds and bitter cold would pierce the strongest shell.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_BENCH">Ahh, the shining bench has risen for us! Pharloom&#8217;s kindness to we pilgrims is inexhaustible!&lt;page&gt;Please rest, red maiden, and fear not. Our kingdom watches over us all!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BONEGATE_MEET_4">Join your voice with mine, red maiden! You, me, and my lucky chime will sing together until the great gate opens!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_WAKE_2">Hrm? Hoy there! I was looking for somewhere to rest my weary shell and found this cosy station!&lt;hpage&gt;These lands are dangerous. I had thought perhaps some harm had come to you.&lt;page&gt;Harm? O red maiden, have faith! No harm can come to us on this holy ascent! We only need to keep our gaze upwards.&lt;page&gt;Isn&#8217;t this all so terribly grand? The great stone steps, the winds lifting us up like the voices of a choir, and just beyond it all is our pilgrimage&#8217;s end. The great Citadel at last!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_WAKE_1">&lt;hpage&gt;Little pilgrim, do you sleep?</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_CORALDRILLERS_REPEAT">She and her like have red-rocky shells to protect their softnesses. Inside is very sweet! Very hard to crack them open though, so is best to wait. Is always best to wait!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_SPAR_ACCEPT">&lt;hpage&gt;Gladly, Shakra. Upon this stone, let us test our shells.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_BLACK_THREAD_FIRST">Well met, sister. Though the beastly Citadel has finally been slain, still the lands caught beneath it suffer!&lt;page&gt;The evils long done by that cursed place have sunk into the kingdom&#8217;s very foundations, and now they rise up as a black sickness.&lt;hpage&gt;This darkness, it is a curse deadlier than the Haunting... a force from far below that will consume all if given the opportunity.&lt;page&gt;Hmm... Just so! And while wickedness still stalks these lands, our hornlance shall not rest!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BONEGATE_REPEAT">Sturdy gaaaaa-aaate, I don&#8217;t ask you break or beee-eeend,&lt;br&gt;Just open a little for me, and my tall maiden frieeee-eeend!</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_LAKE_MEET">These waters, at land&#8217;s edge... and the shrine atop... our furtive escape... our brief retreat from rule...&lt;page&gt;So many moments spent simple... joyful... free...</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_AID_REPEAT">What say you, sister? Shall we join together in valiant combat?</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_RESCUE_END1">Oh red maiden, sorry to have lured you into such danger!&lt;page&gt;And those poor bugs, bewitched by the thread. No sin could possibly warrant such a fate...&lt;hpage&gt;Your pity is not misplaced, but better suited for another time. For now, you should look to your own care.&lt;page&gt;Ah... yes. I should get these healing supplies back to the pilgrims&#8217; settlement above. My brothers and sisters have waited long enough.</entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_DIVE_CURSED">&lt;hpage&gt;The parasite writhing within my shell has a violent aversion to the void. &lt;hpage&gt;Despite the protection granted by the Everbloom, even now I can feel those wretched roots preventing my descent.&lt;hpage&gt;If I&#8217;m to dive, and cut this land from its black thread curse, I must first find means to extract the intruder within.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_REOFFER">Many foes await us. Shall we duel with one another before moving on?</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_SKULLKING_MEET">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, Nuu. You have travelled far from your lodgings, I was not expecting to meet you in these lowlands.&lt;page&gt;Oh, hello again miss grown-up! Yes, Nuu is not the fastest, but she goes great distances to follow the scent of learnings.&lt;page&gt;And look what Nuu has found! A great big beast, cracked open and broken apart! There is much to learn from him, so Nuu will savour it all slowly.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_QUILL_DESC">With this quill, you can add any new areas you discover to the maps that you own. We pluck these quills from Golpeni hunted by my tribe. Their hollowed shafts make the perfect charting tool.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_PEAK">Child Wielding Needle, how far our wanderings take us! The cold air here bites through our shells as true as any blade. Warm yourself by my lantern while I call. &lt;hpage&gt;Pharloom is a land of harsh extremes. Perhaps that is, in part, why the pilgrims have a culture of testing themselves against it so fervently.&lt;page&gt;Perhaps. When I first encountered them, I had little respect for the weak, rag-bundled bugs. Too cowardly to even carry a weapon!&lt;page&gt;But... Dondakku. Sometimes we judge too quickly. There is a subtle strength to them, though it is difficult for me to truly understand it.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CITADEL_SPA_GREET">Ahh, the caress of this warm water on my weary limbs is welcome indeed. As soothing as a psalm, haha!&lt;page&gt;Will you splishy-splash in the holy bath with me, red maiden? We can sing together to aid in our rejuvenation!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_ROSARY_STRING">Want yer clicky-clackies threaded nice and tight? Old Grindle will do it gladly, if you let &#8216;im snitch a few for hisself...</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_ENCLAVE_MEET2">D-do not judge me a doubter! The Citadel is a holy place indeed, resplendent and vast beyond my wildest hopes!&lt;page&gt;But yet... the grand halls ache with silence, and I see suffering in the shadows wherever I peer too deeply.&lt;page&gt;Fear, and pain... why were these things allowed into our paradise? Have my brothers and sisters not yet earned their holy reward?</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC1">...Crossed weapons, sleeping of course, but shaped unlike any you&#8217;ve seen before...&lt;page&gt;...To travel underneath is one thing, but travelling up above may require a different sort of sight...&lt;hpage&gt;Sir Herald... It seems rare coincidence for us to meet in this distant land. Unless, perhaps, you followed me here?&lt;page&gt;...A path that meets itself is an ill portent indeed. Those who peer sideways know well enough...&lt;page&gt;</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_LUCKY_DICE">Nice little pair of rolly-rollies we got &#8216;ere. Sure to bring luck to any snitchin&#8217; expedition...</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC3">...The elements do not conspire against you. They have their own desires...&lt;page&gt;...When one spies a great peak, the natural inclination is to begin climbing...&lt;page&gt;...The little left-behind... you&#8217;ve decided, then? A companion for the journey...</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_VERDANIA_BOSS_2">&lt;hpage&gt;Feel guilt at your absence, sir, but know the end was inexorable, the outcome set, whether you remained or not.&lt;page&gt;Do not seek to console me, warrior... This memory is mine alone... I&#8217;ll not brook your brutish intrusion...&lt;page&gt;You who dare trespass this sacred chamber, ready yourself... to see us, and know us, Verdania&#8217;s rulers, together in our finest form...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_GREYMOOR_REPEAT">If you choose to rest here, I will watch over you, Child Wielding Needle. These charts require long attention and my own sleep is far off yet.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BELLBEAST">Beasty, beastly, big fat beast! Strong as a boulder, or a rock at least! Let&#8217;s sing together &#8216;til you&#8217;re released!&lt;page&gt;Oh! Look here red maiden, this poor creature is all tangled up in white bindings! Surely you know a song for unsticking such stickiness?&lt;hpage&gt;It will take a power greater than song to break these bindings, little one. In my current diminished state even I can not cut through them.&lt;page&gt;Well, worry not! If something is needed, the road will bring it to us!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_PIN_BELLWAY_NAME">Bellway Pins</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_EXITED_RETURN">Nimble bug! You abandoned the race? Surely it was only an error?&lt;page&gt;In the pursuit of speed all reason can ofttimes be lost, left in the wind as it were.&lt;page&gt;At least you seem recovered of your lapse. And surely you are eager now?&lt;page&gt;We must sprint on! Let us soar swift together!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_PIN_BENCH_NAME">Bench Pins</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_DUSTPENS">Child Wielding Needle. These are stale roads, ill-fitted for warriors such as ourselves.&lt;page&gt;There is fair combat here against the roach-beasts and their keepers, but the air is sickly and the water writhes with parasites.&lt;hpage&gt;This environment is harsh indeed, though life seems to adapt itself to many hardships. Do you believe your master travelled these roads?&lt;page&gt;I had thought not at first, but upon closer search I found the fragments of a trail winding through these fetid ruins.&lt;page&gt;Perhaps she saw something here that I did not? Her senses are often keen where mine are clouded.</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_AID_MEET_BEAST">Hold there, sister! A great beast stalks this land, swooping and screeching like an ill-mannered tyrant!&lt;page&gt;Zaza has been following the creature&#8217;s scent, and now I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;re almost upon it! We&#8217;re so close my whiskers are bristling!&lt;page&gt;Such a beast is worthy quarry for the valiant, aye? What say you, shall we hunt the creature together?</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_PIN_SHOP_DESC">Many of Pharloom&#8217;s bugs have useful equipment and items to trade. It would do you well to keep track of their locations with this pin.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These pins will mark vendors on your map.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_THIEF_CLAW">Basic tool&#8217;o the job, here. Throw your big needle and scratch shinies straight off your target&#8217;s shell!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_MOSSGROTTO_NAME">Mosslands Map</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC7_B">...Oh. Wyrm child. No surprise it&#8217;s you who meets me here.&lt;page&gt;Following me are you? Or calling me? It is true I would not have sought the lands below if not for your grand actions within them.&lt;page&gt;But now, having journeyed their breadth, what singular sights I beheld... Flaming lakes, tangled woods, caves consumed by sand and frost...&lt;page&gt;Remarkable things all, though given their void claimed state it seems you and I may be the last to hold those memories.&lt;hpage&gt;I cannot allow that outcome, Herald. I act now to save that place, both for myself and for those bugs still alive within.&lt;hpage&gt;As one who has seen so much, tell me simply, do you believe my efforts in vain?&lt;page&gt;Me? Certainly you can ask, but I cannot provide good answer. I&#8217;ve no mind for outcomes. Always my vision is too clouded by the present.&lt;page&gt;Only the journey... the now. For myself, that is the purpose, and as far as my sight can see.&lt;page&gt;If any other could come to understand that state, Wyrm child, I suspect it may be you... &lt;page&gt;Though maybe not yet, not this present, hmmm? Maybe in a future far, when your actions might hail me so again?&lt;page&gt;Alas, from these quaking caves it is past time I made my swift exit. Ours each may be long and winding roads, but I hope you too come to know the many joys upon the path...</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_AID_REFUSE">You would fight alone, sister? You would be undefeatable with me by your side! And Zaza also! You need only ask, and our hornlance would be yours.</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC7_A">...Do they realise it would only be the beginning? If they cleave themselves free, they would need to find their way anew...</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_REPEAT_FINAL">My hopes go with you, red maiden. They will follow you into the deepest darkness, and beyond!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_WILDS_DESC">Fierce red-shells nest across these wide caverns. Battle with them is most intense. Impressive are the warriors of Pharloom.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_DOCKS_NAME">Deep Docks Map</entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_DIVE_3">&lt;hpage&gt;Even if only your shadow remains, to release your mother&#8217;s grip my blade would see it slain.&lt;page&gt;Then why hold, even at this moment? Surely terror hasn&#8217;t suddenly claimed even your hardened heart?&lt;page&gt;Take the final plunge, spider. Join us in my drowning palace, and let oblivion swallow us all.&lt;hpage&gt;Oblivion may take you, child. My own life, I shall not sacrifice.&lt;hpage&gt;I have survived the fury of your land. I have borne its barbs and its blades, and I have seen wonder behind its dangers.&lt;hpage&gt;But always, child, I remain a daughter of Hallownest. And the void below all things, that darkness I will fear no longer...</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_BONEFOREST_REFUSE">Oooh! Greedy are you? Mean to poor li&#8217;l snitchbugs like us? Won&#8217;t survive out there without our secrets, oh no no!</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_OFFER_3">Our last race was grand, yes? But I see now I set too mild a challenge for one as spritely as yourself!&lt;page&gt;I prepared only to race, but you arrived bringing destiny! In you my wish may finally be granted, the barriers of speed broken wide!&lt;page&gt;Are you prepared nimble bug? The time is upon us. The final test for the swift and spry!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_COMPLETE_REPEAT">Miss grown-up has hunted much, so soon is time for Nuu to venture out, she thinks. Keep your sights keen, for to meet in the wilds would be a delight!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SLAB_EARLY_NOTMET">O-hoho! You&#8217;re lookin&#8217; a little stuck there! What a pity!&lt;hpage&gt;Are you too a prisoner here, small bug? If we ally our efforts, escape could be made that much easier.&lt;page&gt;Hoho, you jestin&#8217;? There ain&#8217;t no allies in prison! Just throw yourself against the walls in there while I go sniffin&#8217; for goodies! </entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_SCROLL_INSPECT">A scroll detailing the scents and tastes of Pharloom&#8217;s various bugs and beasts.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_INTRO_ACT3">Miss grown-up! Nuu had fear that the awful rumblings of the world or sticky black threads had snatched you away from her!&lt;hpage&gt;I have survived, Nuu, and shall fight on while my strength remains.&lt;hpage&gt;The kingdom has grown darkly dangerous, but this hearth-home seems to still provide some safety. I suggest you remain here for now.&lt;page&gt;Of course! Nuu shall stay inside. The sickening sense of those twisted threads has spoilt the joy of my venturings.&lt;page&gt;You though, miss grown-up... is now not the perfect time to fully complete our journal?&lt;page&gt;The world-rumblings will surely have scared up many creatures from their hiding places! So go and hunt, and show sweet Nuu what you learn!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_CITADEL_REFUSE">Why spurn a little duel, sister? Surely it would put us in good stead for the trials ahead!&lt;hpage&gt;If we were to duel it would doubtless be illuminating. Unfortunately, I lack the time for such frivolity. Farewell, sirs.</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_MEET_PT1">&lt;hpage&gt;Cowards. Here you hide, even as you cause your own land&#8217;s demise.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MAGGOTTED">Ka, va! Your shell is ridden with those gruesome maggots. It was a foolish choice of yours to swim in their sickly pools.&lt;hpage&gt;This was by no means desired, Shakra. For now, I think it best you remain at limb&#8217;s length. &lt;hpage&gt;I shall not abide this infestation long. By Silk or by rest I shall soon see myself cleansed. </entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_WRONG_GATE">Nimble bug! You seem to have lost your way upon the course. Surely it was only an error? You already seem recovered of your lapse.&lt;page&gt;You are eager to run again, yes, yes? Let us soar swift together!</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC6_C"></entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC6_B"></entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC6_A">...One can visit the past, but then memories become contradictory...&lt;page&gt;...When the call rings out again, will you let your previous actions cloud your vision?&lt;page&gt;...By claw, by voice... History always rises to meet us...</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_DECLINED">Oooh, ma. Miss grown-up, you deny poor Nuu? So sour!&lt;page&gt;Think of all the delectable learnings can we dig out of the creatures living here!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_JUDGESTEPS_NAME">Blasted Steps Map</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_HERO_WIN_AFTER_WISH">But wait! Before you depart. Your exceptional skill requires an equally fine reward!&lt;page&gt;This fine shard of ancient mask is yours! Take it. Cherish it. And know, you shall forever have my thanks.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_CRESTSOCKET">This is a fine shiny-shiny, ain&#8217;t it? Those dirty old raggedies like to carry these around, and we like to snitch &#8216;em away when we can! O-ho-ho!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_GIVE">Ooooh ma, you make Nuu so happy! Hunt down the creatures of this land, and record them in this scroll!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_CORALCAVERNS">&lt;hpage&gt;Fair greetings Shakra, in these drifts consumed by crust and sand.&lt;hpage&gt;These caverns have returned to nature, but I see evidence of bold structures buried throughout.&lt;page&gt;The shells of their builders rest in a tower above. A grand tribe they seemed, and strong fighters I&#8217;m sure. Alas, they exist now only as hardened husks.&lt;page&gt;Lament, Child Wielding Needle! We lived too late to match their claws.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_PILGRIMSREST_MEET">Don&#8217;t despair, pilgrim frieeeee-eeend,&lt;br&gt;Lift your sight and raise your voice!&lt;br&gt;Have no fear, pilgrim truuuuu-uuuuue,&lt;br&gt;Believing is a happy choice!&lt;page&gt;Hoy there! Aren&#8217;t these fields marvellous? And above us are the bountiful moors, where every pilgrim can fill their belly!&lt;hpage&gt;These hot fields are a wonder indeed, but hunters prowl the long grass. Playing your instrument will only alert them to your presence.&lt;page&gt;Well then, alert them I shall! For where many gather, great songs are sung!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_CITADEL_ENCLAVE">&lt;hpage&gt;Some pilgrims have made an encampment in a safer place than this, high on the other side of the Citadel.&lt;hpage&gt;They would surely allow you to stay there, if you could resist causing them mischief.&lt;page&gt;An en-camp-ment, eh? Sounds like a jolly place for old Grindle! Mayhaps we&#8217;ll have a sniff around later.&lt;page&gt;That&#8217;s a good tip, that. And you&#8217;ve just done given it to us for free! O-hoho, head fulla muck you got!</entry>
<entry name="DICE_PILGRIM_HORNETDEPLETED">Well well! Seems I won the last of your rosaries. Luck is granted to the faithful, it is sung, so I must be very faithful indeed.&lt;page&gt;If you happen on any more rosaries though, I&#8217;d be well happy to play you again.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_E_NAME">Bronze Marker</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_JOURNAL_GIVEN_ACT3">&lt;hpage&gt;Already, I have cut down many of this lands inhabitants, but I agree, documenting those creatures is a worthwhile undertaking.&lt;hpage&gt;If time still permits, I shall do as you wish.&lt;page&gt;Ma! How wonderful for Nuu! Go now! Hunt, and prey, and begin our learning!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SAVED1">Hoho, free at last! Locked up in here much too long, we was. Nasty place to keep a poor little snitchbug like Grindle.&lt;page&gt;Hoy, you&#8217;re smellin&#8217; fancy! You got some pockets under your cloak? Hidin&#8217; away some goodies for us to pilfer?&lt;hpage&gt;Beware your greed, thief. You&#8217;d be dead before your claw reached my cloak.&lt;page&gt;O-hoho! Never mind then, bully. Plenty of tasties lying around for us down here. We smells &#8216;em!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_SHELLWOOD_NAME">Shellwood Map</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MASTER_AFTER">&lt;hpage&gt;Your master has been found, Shakra. Your task in these lands is finished. Will you now return to your tribe? &lt;page&gt;I shall not return, Hornet Wielding Needle... I cannot. To leave my tribe&#8217;s nest-plains, that journey has only one direction. &lt;page&gt;This has always been our way, our long leaving, for those few who survive till age seeks to claim their shell, and those fewer who choose to send them on.&lt;page&gt;But these lands, Pharloom... My nest-plains I once saw so grand, now they become small. A place for birth, and growing, but a place too narrow to live a bug&#8217;s life full.</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_CARMELITA_CORPSE">This giant, old ant... Her death seems recent, but her presence here... &lt;page&gt;Was it her? Could it be? The strength that sustained these caves? If so, what will happen now?&lt;hpage&gt;They will wither and fade... And you may sadly know it was my needle that brought her end.&lt;page&gt;You, miss? Buy why? Why destroy something so vital? &lt;hpage&gt;It is a difficult thing to explain simply... Her strength was needed, what was left, to cut Pharloom free of its black thread threat. It was a savage act, no doubt, but the reason was just.&lt;hpage&gt;Know, in time, these caves may see opportunity to regrow, flourish even, though that rebirth is itself a task enormous... longer than a lifetime, many lifetimes.&lt;hpage&gt;For that task to succeed, it will fall to bugs like you to sow the first seeds.</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_HORNET_RITUAL_CURSED">&lt;page=M&gt;Hold it, Old One! That intruder writhing within your shell... &lt;page=S&gt;Our ritual ain&#8217;t gonna work while that cruel creature&#8217;s present. We&#8217;d be tugging at its memories as much as your own.&lt;hpage&gt;Then free me of the affliction. Surely you have the skill?&lt;page=S&gt;Not for this! Our power&#8217;s all of soul and that thing&#8217;s all physical. You&#8217;re gonna need more traditional tools of healing.&lt;page=B&gt;Seek the one exiled from Bellhart, little Yarnaby. She was chased out into those soaked moors, last I heard.&lt;page=B&gt;She&#8217;d have the tools for the task, and the cunning to have survived till now.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_PIN_BENCH_DESC">When travelling in unfriendly lands, it is important to remember safe places to camp.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These pins will mark benches and other rest spots on your map.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_SPLINTERQUEEN_REPEAT">Nuu takes time with her creatures, she must inspect closely. Thick arms, flakey hair, delicate eyes... Nuu will inspect it all!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_FINAL_SONG">Maiden, strong, wreathed in red,&lt;br&gt;Shield her shell, bless her thread!&lt;br&gt;She fights for us until the end,&lt;br&gt;Please protect my dearest friee-end!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_CORALCAVERNS_REPEAT">If chance allows, visit the tower above. It is an impressive sight, not overgrown by the crust upon these caverns, but rather formed full of the material itself. &lt;page&gt;If the old tribe of this place were able to guide its growth to such grand degree... then they possessed a power to rival even that Citadel.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MEET_BONE_1D">These strange, shuffling pilgrims... In the camp below they were docile enough, but up here they seem to have lost their senses. They cry out to the darkness and attack their fellow travellers.&lt;page&gt;Yakkanesh! Keep your weapon drawn and your bearings true! The way ahead is winding, and to lose one&#8217;s way invites only death.&lt;page&gt;I am a navigator amongst my tribe and have been making maps of these lands. I can trade them with you, and supplies, if you wish.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_RESULT_2">Ma, ma! Much hunting has you done, and so many sweet little creatures in our records!&lt;page&gt;Nuu is drooling from such excess of learnings! Please keep working, miss grown-up!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MEET_BONE_1B">In my land, that is the way warriors greet each other. For though you are a child barely hatched, you are also a warrior. Your stance, your weapon, your movements all proclaim it so.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SLAB_EARLY">O-hoho! You&#8217;re lookin&#8217; a little stuck there! What a pity!&lt;hpage&gt;We meet again, little thief. Are you familiar with this place?&lt;hpage&gt;If we ally our efforts, our escape could be made that much easier.&lt;page&gt;Hoho, you jestin&#8217;? There ain&#8217;t no allies in prison! You can just throw yourself against the walls in there while I go sniffin&#8217; for goodies!</entry>
<entry name="GREENPRINCE_SIT_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;Safe journey, tall bug.&lt;page&gt;This is Pharloom, warrior. Safety is a myth.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_TUBE_PIN_NAME">Ventrica Pins</entry>
<entry name="SETH_FESTIVAL_MEET">&lt;hpage&gt;Greetings, Seth. It is a welcome surprise to see you here amongst these festivities.&lt;page&gt;Hullo, hullo! Yes, my wandering was long and I began to fear I would meet my end in those sticky swamps below.&lt;page&gt;How lucky I was to stumble upon the home of these friendly revellers!&lt;page&gt;They said I could be a flea here with them, so of course I agreed. Seems as good a place as any to call home, at least for a time.&lt;page&gt;Now I just need to grow a little fur and sprout some wings, eh? Ha ha!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_SHADOW_DESC">Swamps born in the Citadel&#8217;s shadow. There is evidence the waters here once ran clear.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_SHELLWOOD_DESC">Tangled roads choked beneath bramble and root. The flora is often as deadly as the creatures who call this place home. </entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_EXTRA_REPEAT">What say you, nimble bug? The test of endurance remains at your ready! Let us stride fast forth!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_BLACK_THREAD_REPEAT">Zaza and I will fight through these cursed lands until every last one of the black-twisted fiends has been cut down!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_HORNET_RITUAL_CURSED_REPEAT">&lt;page=M&gt;Hurry, Old One. The ritual can&#8217;t commence while you remain host to that writhing root.&lt;page=B&gt;Seek the one exiled from Bellhart, little Yarnaby. She was chased out into those soaked moors, last I heard.&lt;page=B&gt;She&#8217;d have the tools for the task, and the cunning to have survived till now.</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_HUNTERCAMP">The red-shells, hiding through the fields, stalking the boney beasts. They are part of it, somehow, the life that flourishes here.&lt;page&gt;Even haunted, they seem to lose less of themselves... What anchor allows them to retain such strength?</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BONEGATE_MEET_2a">Oh, but of course I sing! I am Sherma, a pilgrim just like you. I hear the call of the great Citadel just like every other devout soul.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_TRAPPED1">Hoy! Hoyyyy! You there! Get us out of here! Since when&#8217;s a little light thievery worth a lifelong sentence?</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CARETAKER_TALK1">Our great Citadel has lost its voice, and now the black threads rise up to tear its shell apart. I fear holy Pharloom is truly dying...&lt;page&gt;But I still have hope, red maiden! Though kingdoms may fall, life endures still, and we bugs can build our lands anew!&lt;hpage&gt;I share your hope, Sherma. Remember though that whatever is built next belongs not to the past, but to you.&lt;hpage&gt;Your instincts are strong. Let it be those that guide you, rather than any reverence toward a kingdom&#8217;s corpse.&lt;page&gt;Oho, you flatter me so! But it is my fellows who shall guide me, those whose voices sing out still, even in these ruined times...</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_BLACK_THREAD">Hahhh... well met, sister. The task of hunting down these black-twisted fiends is no small one, eh? Still, we must not rest! Not while the cries of the innocent echo from every corner of the kingdom!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_ITEM_THIEF_CHARM">Sign yourself as a snitch! And scoop up more rosaries from your bested foes. Just watch it when you&#8217;re snitchin&#8217; that you don&#8217;t lose sum&#8217;a your own...</entry>
<entry name="LACE_CITADEL_MEET_BATTLE_SKIPPED">What&#8217;s this? The spider arrives at last, here to stand acquiver at our startling Citadel.&lt;hpage&gt;Pale child, you return only to mock? Your lands have yet to prove my match. This sleeping Citadel shall be no different.&lt;page&gt;Spider, dear. Why must you remain so distressingly... optimistic? The power that waits above, you cannot conceive, her who would snuff that hope with barely a glance.&lt;hpage&gt;Fool child. You still think me blind to the form of your liege? Having coming this far?&lt;hpage&gt;This land&#8217;s grandeur, the devotion of its bugs, and the curse that befalls them. The signs are clear.&lt;hpage&gt;Your kingdom is in the thrall of a creature beyond bug, one of that higher caste.&lt;hpage&gt;Whatever its desire for my Silk and my shell, it shall find I&#8217;m quite attached to both.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_REPEAT">Is hard work, learning so much from creatures, but for Nuu is very fulfilling. Now go and hunt, and prey, miss grown-up!</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SHOP_INTRO_ACT3">Hoy there, fancy bug! How you farin&#8217;, now that the &#8216;ole world&#8217;s creakin&#8217; and crackin&#8217; around us? Desperately needin&#8217; some supplies, I&#8217;ll wager! Heh heh!&lt;hpage&gt;You seem in good spirits, thief. Are you not disturbed by the great rending of the kingdom?&lt;page&gt;Heh, end of the world don&#8217;t bother ol&#8217; Grindle none. We&#8217;ll just go find another one to plunder, won&#8217;t we?</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_HORNET_MEMORY_REOFFER">&lt;page=M&gt;Our spells&#8217;re woven, our parts prepared. Whenever you&#8217;re ready, lay up on the dais and we&#8217;ll begin.&lt;page=M&gt;Best you don&#8217;t dawdle now. Pharloom&#8217;s time is short, and those hearts won&#8217;t go on beating forever.</entry>
<entry name="GREEN_PRINCE_CLOVER_MEET_2">No more talk, warrior. Permit me this final moment of memorial.&lt;hpage&gt;As you wish, sir. I shall disturb you no longer.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_DECLINE">&lt;hpage&gt;Another time perhaps, sir. My own tasks cannot be easily ignored.&lt;page&gt;Then I shall continue to train in anticipation of that future moment!&lt;page&gt;Having met, it is inevitable. Fate calls us to compete!</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_CORALDRILLERS_MEET">Oh, welcome miss grown-up! Come to inspect the red-rocky creatures, like Nuu? We have found a very big one. Fresh, but not too fresh!&lt;hpage&gt;A pair of beasts attacked me here, burrowing through the stone with their spiral shells. I cut this one down and the other fled.&lt;page&gt;Ooooh ma! Really? Nuu wishes that she had the pair! She could have studied much. Unlucky, to miss such a big feast of learnings!</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_BLACK_THREAD_EXHAUSTED_REPEAT">We must press on... There is so much more... for us to do...</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_DOCKS_REPEAT">I see much wasted effort in these docks. There is too much flourish to the form of it all. The ways of others are strange indeed...</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_OFFER_2">Nimble bug! We both know our previous run was only warm-up, yes? Only a tiny test to prepare for the real match, Hoi hoi!&lt;page&gt;Well that match is now! A new track worthy of your skill, and mine. No longer merely a test!&lt;page&gt;Meet the challenge and my speed full. Let us break through our limits and see what waits beyond!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_B_DESC">You can use these to mark places of importance or reminders on your map.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;With these I often mark the locations of worthy foes.</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_ALREADY_ACCEPTED">Hoi hoi! A nimble opponent appears. At last! At last!&lt;hpage&gt;I was intrigued by the challenge you issued on the bell settlement&#8217;s wishwall, sir, though having reached this place I wonder at your choice of location.&lt;hpage&gt;If you seek challengers you should choose somewhere less far afield. It is rare chance any bug would journey to a cavern so distant.&lt;page&gt;True, perhaps. Though once discovered, could there be a more perfect spot? This giant, boney body, so distant from Pharloom&#8217;s ails.&lt;page&gt;Here, freely, we can test our speed and our sleek shells. Here we may race!&lt;page&gt;You must be eager to step to the task, challenger? Fulfil my wish! Let us discover our limits together! </entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_ZAPNEST_SLAP2">Uahhhhh... So close... Nuu could almost taste it.</entry>
<entry name="GILLY_ACT3">Ho! Are you observing them too, hunter? The red-shells are plentiful here, stalking these vast grassy plains and the last of its boney beasts.&lt;page&gt;Compared to the caves below, this lush growth feels even greater. Have we crawled close to the source of their sustenance?&lt;page&gt;I must discover its secret! I will! By my father&#8217;s wish, and for hope that our dying lands might find means to endure.&lt;hpage&gt;Just be careful, young one. I urge you. Here you&#8217;ve reached the ants&#8217; heart-domain.&lt;hpage&gt;There may be discoveries worth making, but a single mistake will see your shell&#8217;s sharp end.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_MEET_OPENED">Hoy! Did you see it, red maiden? The great gate heard my song and, in its infinite and ancient kindness, opened the way forward for us!&lt;page&gt;What luck, for us to meet at this moment! We can set off on the great road together!&lt;page&gt;Or p&#8217;raps I&#8217;ll tarry here just a little longer. I want to sing a song of gratitude to this noble gate!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_MEET_BONE_2">In these lands names are given freely, are they not? I am Shakra, Wielding Rings. If our hunts intertwine again, I will have new maps to trade.&lt;page&gt;Until then, farewell, Child Wielding Needle.</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_ENCLAVE_HEALING">This place is holy, yes... but I worry at the suffering of our fellow pilgrims. So many are hurt or exhausted!&lt;hpage&gt;Your doubts and worries will not heal them, little one.&lt;hpage&gt;If you would aid your fellows, you can start by dressing their wounds. The simple rags found around the settlement will do for bandages.&lt;page&gt;Oh, that&#8217;s an excellent idea, red maiden! Normally I&#8217;d think a song would suffice, but... yes, more direct action is certainly needed.&lt;page&gt;And the Citadel itself shall provide the materials! Praise be to this holiest of holy places!</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_ENCLAVE_REPEAT">Fear not, brothers and sisters! If we work hard and keep our faith, the Citadel will provide for us... I have no doubt!</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_DEEP_MEMORY3">&lt;page=M&gt;The hearts you seek, we can share their locations as best we know.&lt;page=M&gt;Three will be needed to construct our spell and draw clear memory of the flower from your Silk.&lt;page=S&gt;Bring us the hearts, Old One. Make&#8217;em beat, fierce and final. See for yourself the forgotten strength of this land of bugs before we burn those memories in its saving.</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MARKER_B_NAME">Ring Marker</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_AID_ACCEPT">&lt;hpage&gt;The battle ahead may indeed be arduous. I accept your offer of aid, sirs.&lt;page&gt;Gurrrro! Yes! No force in the kingdom can withstand our might! Lead on, sister! Zaza and I will be close behind!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_HUNTERSNEST_DESC">Burrowed paths of the red-shells. Their stores and shrines are frequent throughout. These tunnels must grant them swift passage about the fields below. </entry>
<entry name="LACE_ABYSS_LAKE_DIVE_CURSED_REPEAT">&lt;hpage&gt;If I&#8217;m to dive, and cut this land from its black thread curse, I must first find means to extract the intruder within.</entry>
<entry name="GREENPRINCE_SIT_MEET">So I am freed, despite no request of mine for aid.&lt;hpage&gt;And I do not ask gratitude. The key merely fit the lock. If you choose, stay in here and wait till your shell hardens to crust.&lt;page&gt;No. I shall depart shortly. With my way clear, my wish again propels me, though I tried to avoid it.&lt;hpage&gt;Then safe journey, tall bug. I&#8217;ll not pry further. Clearly you bear your own burden. </entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_CORAL_REWAKE">Mm, mrm? Oh, hoy again!&lt;page&gt;I hadn&#8217;t meant to drop off like that. It&#8217;s hard to stay awake in such a cosy place, isn&#8217;t it?</entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_BONEGATE_MEET">Oh hear me pray, please hear me sing,&lt;br&gt;My path&#8217;s ahead, but here&#8217;s the thing,&lt;br&gt;I can&#8217;t squeeze past, o gate of bone,&lt;br&gt;So please wake up, and help...oh?</entry>
<entry name="SNAILS_ACT3_HEART_HINT_CORAL">&lt;page=M&gt;Up top of those caves lost to wind and sand rests a crusted old ruler, a once great warrior king.&lt;page=M&gt;In their prime, they and their order held half of Pharloom under hardened claw. Some bugs relished that strength. Most lived in fear of it.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_MEET">Oooh ma! Sweet surprise for Nuu! You are adult, yes? Fully grown? Ready to hunt?&lt;hpage&gt;Certainly I am no child, young one.&lt;page&gt;Perfect then! Nuu must ask a wish! For her, you would seek Pharloom&#8217;s many fabulous bugs and cut them.&lt;page&gt;Cut them with your blade! Cut them with your mature spirit! Cut them with your savage adult heart!&lt;page&gt;Would you help Nuu? Could you take her scroll, and fill its pages with the learnings of your cuts?</entry>
<entry name="GARMOND_MEET">Guurroooo! Scoundrel! Fiend! Who dares wake brave Garmond from his well needed kip?&lt;hpage&gt;I&#8217;ve no intent to disturb, sir bug. I am merely passing these towers and sought to better understand the lay of the place.&lt;page&gt;Hmmph! Knowing the battlefield? A warrior&#8217;s reason! Just look at you! Your stance and blade, almost alone they declare a fight.&lt;page&gt;As the bravest of knights, if direct challenge were offered, honour would see noble Garmond accept!&lt;page&gt;Fortunate that seems not your intent. In truth, I&#8217;m still sleeping off something of an altercation myself. Had our meeting called for a knightly duel, you&#8217;d not have had the luck to behold my finest form.</entry>
<entry name="GRINDLE_SHOP_INTRO">Hoy then, what&#8217;s a fancy-prancy bug like you creepin&#8217; into Grindle&#8217;s cosy little nook for?&lt;page&gt;Heard we had some nice stuff, did ya? O-hoho! All kinds of tasty goodies find their way here, that&#8217;s for sure.&lt;hpage&gt;I care little for how you procured your goods, thief. If you have something worth trading, I may part with my rosaries.&lt;page&gt;Well, we never say no to a fair swap, heh heh! Now take a look at what we&#8217;s got...</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_EXTRA_WIN_POST">Now I shall remain, and train. And know! Though I have no more rewards to give, you are welcome to grace my track, as many times as you wish.</entry>
<entry name="SETH_GREYMOOR_REPEAT">The sharp-faced bugs of these drizzled caves love to swoop and play, don&#8217;t they? If only I could understand their beautiful language...</entry>
<entry name="MRMUSH_LOC5">...At the bottom of a well, you can only look up. The past is hidden from those who look forward...&lt;page&gt;...Those echoes may guide you still. Yes, that&#8217;s true. For the kind-hearted, a weapon can also be a friend...&lt;page&gt;...You&#8217;re so eager to follow in her footsteps. But what are you leaving for those who come next?</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_ITEM_MAP_SHADOW_NAME">Bilewater Map</entry>
<entry name="SPRINTMASTER_HERO_WIN_REPEAT">Hoof... Always you impress... nimble bug...&lt;page&gt;As many times as you may, let us speed forth! Gladly will I strive to match your spritely grace. </entry>
<entry name="SHERMA_PILGRIMSREST_TALK1">This poor traveller finds her resolve waning. When I first greeted her, her voice was so hoarse I scarcely heard it!&lt;page&gt;&#8217;Tis no cause for worry, though. My song will lift her from her torpor! Join your voice with mine, red maiden, and together we shall rouse our fellow pilgrim!</entry>
<entry name="MAPPER_GENERIC_JUDGESTEPS_REPEAT">In time, even these great steps will be swept away by the sands. Nothing is immovable.</entry>
<entry name="HUNTER_FAN_SPLINTERQUEEN_MEET">Ooh ma ma! Look here, miss grown-up! Very fascinating creature here, all dead in bits now, but still good!&lt;page&gt;She takes the shape of the woods for her body, and her hair like bitter leaves! Clever, thinks Nuu!&lt;hpage&gt;This creature staked its territory here and attacked as I passed through.&lt;hpage&gt;You should not linger long. Her tribe remains hidden amongst the branches, disguised and waiting to strike.&lt;page&gt;Oooh! So the cutting-up was done by you? Nuu gives her warm thanks! Now Nuu can inspect this creature well, all its gooey insides and crunchy shell!</entry>
</entries>
